虽然他为了当总统  付出了很多
"So, even though he wanted to do a lot as President,
但是仅仅上任32天后  就死于肺炎
"he died of pneumonia after only 32 days.
因此  威廉·亨利·哈里森的故事告诉我们
"So, we can all learn from William Henry Harrison
要注意保暖  勤洗手  这样才能拥有更好的免疫系统
"to wear our coats and wash our hands, so we have better immune systems.
说完了
"The end."
安妮  真棒
Good job, Annie.
好了  2号安妮  该你了
Okay, Annie B., your turn.
快下课了吧  我可不想耽误大家的假期时间
You sure there's time? I don't wanna keep anyone from vacation.
先上来
Just get up here.
你的演讲稿呢  在这里
Where's your essay? Up here.
而且还有即兴表演
And it's more of a performance piece.
开始吧
Here we go.
我演讲的总统是富兰克林·德拉诺·罗斯福
My president is Franklin Delano Roosevelt.
他于1932年当选  那时候人人都很穷
He was elected in 1932, when almost everyone was poor.
就像现在一样  不过那时没有英特网
So, pretty much just like now, but without the lnternet.
除了各行业的尖端人才  其他都是穷人
Everyone except the front row, you be the poor people.
饥饿与愤怒  让你咆哮  让你跺脚
You're hungry and mad. So, growl and stomp your feet.
恭喜第一排的同学  你们是富人
Front row, good news, you're the rich people.
一边微笑  一边鼓掌  你们比其他人做得好
Laugh and clap like you're better than everybody.
但是富兰克林不想大家都那么穷  于是他给了大家工作
But FDR didn't like it that everyone was poor, so, he gave them all jobs.
他将这项措施  称为新政
He called it the New Deal.
勤奋工作  你就会变得富裕
Work hard, and you get rich.
我拍了一下的  都是富人
So, when I tap you, you're rich.
他让人们修路赚钱
He had people build roads and got paid.
砍树也可以赚钱
Cut down trees and got paid.
买房子  上大学都变得简单了
Made it easy to buy a house, go to college.
很快  整个国家的人民都很高兴
Soon, the whole country was happy.
富人们  你们也别担心
But don't worry, rich people.
你们还是比其他人富裕  因为你变得更富裕了
You're still better than everyone because you get even richer!
说得好  安妮  祝大家假期愉快
Good job, Annie. Have a good vacation, everyone!
你可以及时赶到吗  我一向都可以的
You gonna make it in time? I always do.
我们帮你做掩护  祝你好运  运气是给失败者准备的
We'll cover for you. Good luck. Luck's for suckers.
明天...明天
Tomorrow... To-To-Tomorrow
明天
To-Tomorrow
我们的生活举步维艰
It's the hard-knock life for us
不好意思  你的车还剩多少时间归还  还有10分钟
Excuse me! Do you have any time left? I have about 10 minutes.
我来帮你还吧  真的吗
I'll return it for you. Really?
我保证
Promise.
谢谢
Thanks!
请不要靠近车门
Stand clear of the closing doors, please.
我觉得我会喜欢  我确定我会喜欢
I think I'm gonna like it I'm sure I'm gonna like it
我觉得我会喜欢
I think I'm gonna like it here
10  9  8  7  6
Ten, nine, eight, seven, six,
5  4  3  2  1
five, four, three, two, one.
欢呼吧
Light it up!
谁想要免费的斯塔克斯手机呢
How many of you guys want some free Stacks phones, huh?
我听不见
I can't hear you!
安妮 纽约奇缘
班尼特过来订位了吗
Any reservations for Bennett?
亲爱的  我说过了
Honey, I told you.
要是有任何一个  可能是你父母的人来这里
If anyone I think could even remotely be your parents walk in,
我都会告诉你的  哪怕只有一点点可能
I'm gonna let you know. And I mean remotely.
不管是班尼特  森尼特  珀马格拉尼特
Name's Bennett, Senate, Pomegranate,
黑人  白人
black, white, other.
我都会告诉你
I'll let you know.
不管怎样  我猜你还是会继续等下去的  是的
I'm guessing you're gonna wait anyway. Yep.
拿着你的免费斯塔克斯手机  绝不漏接一个电话
Get your free Stacks phone. Never drop a call.
谢谢  太好了
Thanks, thanks. Cool.
免费的斯塔克斯手机
Free Stacks phone. Okay?
谢谢  谢谢  不客气
Thank you. Thank you. All right.
女士  这个给你
And there we are, ma'am.
免费的斯塔克斯手机  绝不漏接一个电话
Free Stacks phone. Never drop a call.
我绝对会选你做市长的
I'm totally gonna vote for you for mayor now.
你知道吗  这个活动跟竞选没有关系
Yeah, well, you know what? This isn't a campaign event.
不过我很喜欢你这句话
But I would totally love that.
好了  活动到此为止  谢谢
Okay, that's it. We're done. Thanks.
我得好好洗一洗  我觉得我快崩溃了  是啊
Hose me down. I feel like I'm on fire. Yeah.
你应该洗洗你的舌头
You should clean your tongue.
你亲了好几个小孩  别传染腹绞痛了
You kissed a few babies. You don't want to catch colic.
你说的没错  威廉
You know what? You're right. Will!
你握了500只手  你说说是什么感觉
You shake 500 hands, and you tell me how you feel, huh?
就像是动物园管理员
Feel like a zookeeper.
娶我吧  威廉  好的
Marry me, Will! Okay, sure.
抱歉
Sorry.
没关系  我只是过来吃油煎酥卷的
It's okay. I just come for the cannoli.
下周五见  好的
I'll see you next Friday? You know it.
嘿  小姑娘  情况怎样  没消息
Hey, girl. How'd it go? Nah.
我可以用下  当然可以
Can I? Sure.
只要你把这些送给我的女神
As long as you give those to my lady.
谢谢
Thanks.
别动
Freeze!
我说了别动  你这个小鬼
I said freeze, you little rat.
我知道你听见了
I know you heard me.
快过来
Get over here.
这是卢送给你的
These are from Lou.
这一看就知道是卢送的
They look like they're from Lou.
我会告诉他  你很喜欢
I'll tell him you loved them.
你以为大家喜欢一个  伶牙俐齿的小女孩吗
You think the world wants a smart-mouthed little girl?
不喜欢  或者说  你不该在这儿的
No, they don't, or you wouldn't be here.
让你待在这儿的唯一原因是
And the only reason you are here is
国家每周会给我157美元
because I get $157 a week from the state.
相信我  其实根本不值得的
Which, believe me, is not worth it.
我应该用皮带  把你绑起来  你这个小鬼
I should put a leash on you, you little...
你真漂亮
You're so pretty.
我以前是个闪耀的明星
I used to be a bright star.
我以前在世上最大的乐队  C+C音乐工厂
I was in the biggest band in the world, C+C Music Factory.
准备参加阿赛尼尔秀的
About to go on Arsenio Hall Show.
1991年9月16号
September 16th, 1991.
我对他们太客气了  我还没上台  就把我炒了
But I was too good for them! Fired me right before I went out on stage.
你的嗓子很好
You have a very pretty voice.
我到死都会守着这个秘密
I will die with that secret!
嘿  你这个小鬼  我还没有说完呢  快回来
Hey, you little monster, I wasn't done with you! Get back here!
我还没有告诉你
I haven't told you
我差点就加入  猫头鹰与河豚鱼乐队了
how I was almost one of Hootie's Blowfish.
我怎么会这样
How did I get here?
你找到他们了吗  没有  不过没关系
Did you find them? Nah, but it's okay.
真遗憾  真遗憾  安妮
So sorry. Sorry, Annie.
那个巫婆会听见我们说话的
The witch will hear us.
他们永远都不会去那间餐馆的
They're never gonna be at that restaurant.
闭嘴  佩珀  他们会去的
Be quiet, Pepper. Yes, they are.
你才闭嘴  伊莎贝拉
You be quiet, lsabella.
安妮永远也找不到她的家人  我们都找不到
Annie's never gonna find her family. None of us are.
别这么说  别听她的  米娅
Don't say that. Don't listen to her, Mia.
很快就会有人收养你了  我保证
You're gonna get adopted. I promise.
你总是这么说  我已经13岁了  没有人想要青少年
You keep saying that. I'm almost 13. No one wants a teenager.
会有人要的  我们的家人肯定在某个地方
Yes, they do. We all have families somewhere.
你可以再读一遍你的留言吗  好的
Can you read your note again? Okay.
天啊  读了一百万遍了吧
Oh, God. For the millionth time?
对  快读  安妮  不过小声点
Yeah, read it, Annie. But quietly.
他们去了多玛尼餐馆  点了两份油煎酥饼
They went to Domani's, ordered two cannolis,
然后给我写了这封留言
and wrote me this note.
"请照顾我们的孩子  她叫安妮
"Please take care of our baby. Her name's Annie.
我们很快就会来接她
"We'll be back to get her soon.
她的脖子上有半个盒式挂链  另一半在我们这儿
"There's half a locket around her neck, and we have the other half,
等我们遇到她了  就能认出她是我们的孩子"
"so when we come for her, you'll know that she's our girl."
我可以看看嘛
Can I see it?
他们会过来找我们的  我保证
They're gonna come back for all of us. I promise.
Maybe far away
Or maybe real nearby
He may be pouring her coffee
She may be straightening his tie!
Maybe in a house
All hidden by a hill
She's sitting playing piano
He's sitting paying a bill!
Betcha they're young
Betcha they're smart
Bet they collect things Like ashtrays, and art!
Betcha they're good
Why shouldn't they be?
Their one mistake
Was giving up me!
So maybe now it's time
And maybe when I wake
They'll be there calling me "baby"
Maybe
Betcha he reads Betcha he reads...
Betcha she sews Betcha she sews...
Maybe she's made me A closet of clothes!
Maybe they're strict
As straight as a line
Don't really care
As long as they're mine
So maybe now this prayer's
Maybe now this prayer...
The last one of its kind
Won't you please come get your "Baby"
Maybe
起来  快起来  小鬼们
Wake up! Wake up, rats. Get out of bed!
还早呢  今天是星期六
It's so early. And it's Saturday.
谢谢你们提醒我时间和日期  现在我们再说说天气吧
Thanks for the time and date. Now, over to Stormy for the weather.
下雨了
It's raining!
市里来电话了  他们要过来检查
The city called. They're coming to inspect.
你们快起来大扫除了
You gotta go and clean this whole place up!
他们没有提前几天通知我们吗
Aren't they supposed to give a couple days' notice?
我是不是应该嫁给乔治·克鲁尼
Aren't I supposed to be married to George Clooney?
快起来打扫
Get out of bed and start cleaning!
乔治·克鲁尼是谁
Who's George Clooney?
问得好  小朋友
Exactly, girlfriend. Exactly.
不打扫干净  就不能吃早餐
No breakfast until this place is spotless!
我好讨厌她
I hate her so much.
要是找到任何零钱  只要超过5美分的都是我的
And if you find any loose change over a nickel, it's mine.
我刚刚正在做一个美梦  我在滑雪  真正的雪
I was having the best dream. I was ice-skating on real, live ice.
还是把美梦留到好事上吧
Save your dreams for good stuff.
比如拿着无限卡购物
Like shopping with an unlimited credit card.
在糖果里游泳
Or swimming in candy.
坐火箭飞到月球上  这些事永远也不可能
Or flying to the moon in a rocket ship. All things that will never happen.
快点  快起来扫地  因为这就是你们的命
Now, clean like your life depends on it. 'Cause it does!
举步维艰
It's the hard-knock life.
等等"举步维艰"  是什么意思
Wait. What does "hard-knock life" mean?
就是生活就像屎一样
It means our life sucks.
那确实
Then, yeah.
It's the hard-knock life for us!
'Steada treated We get tricked!
'Steada kisses We get kicked!
It's the hard-knock life
大扫除的时候别唱歌
Less singing and more cleaning!
要把我的浴室擦得亮堂堂
And make sure my bathroom shines!
不过别碰我的医药箱
But don't touch my medicine cabinet!
It's the hard-knock life for us!
'Steada treated We get tricked!
'Steada kisses We get kicked!
It's the hard-knock life
Don't it feel like the wind is always howling?
Don't it seem like there's never any light?
Once a day don't you wanna throw the towel in?
It's easier than puttin' up a fight
No one's there when your dreams at night get creepy!
No one cares if you grow or if you shrink!
Empty belly life!
Rotten smelly life!
Full of sorrow life!
No tomorrow life!
Santa Claus we never see
Santa Claus What's that? Who's he?
No one cares for you a bit
When you're a foster kid!
It's the hard-knock life!
"要把我的浴室擦得亮堂堂  不过别碰我的医药箱"
"Make my bathroom shine! But don't touch my medicine cabinet!"
好样的  米娅
Good one, Mia.
It's the hard-knock life for us Yank the whiskers from her chin
It's the hard-knock life for us Jab her with a safety pin
'Steada treated, we get tricked Send her to the loony bin
'Steada kisses, we get kicked
对不起
I'm so sorry!
把扫把递给我  来了
Toss me the broom! Incoming.
塑料
Plastic!
纸罐头
Paper! Can!
It's the hard-knock life for us Yank the whiskers from her chin
It's the hard-knock life for us Jab her with a safety pin
No one cares for you a bit Send her to the loony bin
When you're a foster kid!
It's the hard-knock life
我说了  不要唱歌跳舞
I said no singing and dancing!
举步维艰
It's the hard-knock life
检察员来了  给  看书  帮她梳头  你吹这个
The inspector's here. Here, read a book. Braid her hair. Blow on this.
把这些拼好  是凯蒂猫
Put this together. It's a kitty cat.
那我干什么  你祈祷
What should I do? Pray.
我试过了  一点都没用
I've tried. It hasn't worked yet.
来了  好好表现  要表现出我照顾的很好
Okay. Showtime! You guys, act well cared-for.
我们爱你  汉尼根小姐
We love you, Miss Hannigan!
这还是算了  没人会相信的
Take it down a thousand. Nobody's gonna believe that.
快进去
Get under here.
你好
Well, hello there.
你是科琳·汉尼根吗
Are you Colleen Hannigan?
这是我婚前的名字
My maiden name.
不过我还没有结婚  你懂我的意思吧
But I'm not married to it, if you know what I mean.
不懂  快进来  孩子们都在里面玩呢
No. Come on in. The girls are just recreating.
我们从浴室开始检查吧
Should we start here in the bathroom?
为什么  检察员  你怎么这么心急
Why, Mr. lnspector, how forward you are.
不过我都听你的
But I'm right behind you.
什么  什么
What? What?
不是  是我在问你  这边
No, I'm asking you. This way.
等等  你说什么
Wait, what?
你真强壮
Your arms are so strong!
这家伙掉了这个
The dude dropped this.
上面有我们的全部信息
This has all of our information.
真的吗  你在开玩笑吧
Really? You're kidding.
该死的  我住过很多家庭  上面说我住过上百万的家庭
Damn. I've been in a lot of homes. This says I've been in millions.
那是你的社保号  傻瓜
That's your Social Security number, dummy.
社保号是什么
What's a scoso curcurity murder?
就是政府跟进我们用的
It's what the government uses to keep track of us.
等等  这正是我要找的  用它来找我的父母
Wait. This is what I need to get my records. And find my parents.
我要复印下来  想办法出去
I'll copy it down. Plan your exit.
好的
Okay.
人们一般进了浴室  就不想出去了
You know, people come for the bathroom, but they stay for the bedroom.
什么  你懂得
What? You know it.
我可以去图书馆学习吗
Can I go to the library to study?
我们可以等这个
Can we talk about this after
没带结婚戒指的检查员帅哥走了再说嘛
the handsome inspector with no wedding ring is gone?
好吧
Okay.
那我去找牙线
Can I have some floss?
我猜是营养的早餐  害得我塞住牙缝了
I think I have some nutritious breakfast stuck in my teeth.
什么
What?
牙线在医药箱吧
Pretty sure I saw some in the medicine cabinet.
在那里吗
Right there?
我才想起来  我们的牙线用完了
You know, I just remembered. We're out of floss.
你还是拿几本书去图书馆看书吧
Maybe you wanna pick some up on your way to the library.
谢谢  汉尼根小姐
Thank you, Miss Hannigan.
再见  检察员  再见
Bye, Mr. lnspector. Bye, now.
这孩子就像个大人一样
Seems like a great kid.
是的  她很不错
Yeah, she seems great.
我知道怎么回事  你要多少
I know that run. How much you need, mija?
43  55美元
$43.55.
什么时候要  现在
By when? Now?
去抢银行吧  我借你头套
Go rob Bank of America. Here, I'll loan you my mask.
我可以帮你做事  求你了  卢
I'll work for it. Please, Lou.
看你那表情
That face.
去把过期的饮料  从冰箱里拿出来  快去
Take the expired drinks from the cooler. Go ahead.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
你干什么  小鬼
Whoa, what are you doing, girl?
这不是全食公司的嘛  别扔了  改一下保质期
This ain't no Whole Foods. Don't throw them out. Change the date.
我相信任务艰巨  我不会接受"好"
I believe in hard work. I don't just settle for "okay."
我只接受"很棒"
"Great" is all I know.
我的公司跻身于世界前列
I built my company to be a worldwide leader.
对于这个城市  我也想这么做  我想再次成功
And that's what I wanna do with the city. I wanna make it great again.
你还落后了20%的选票
You're 20 points down in the polls.
你已经花费数十亿  却毫无成效
You've got billions to spend and it's not working.
你打算怎么改变大家的想法
How are you gonna change people's minds?
大家都想数一数我的钱
Everybody wants to count my money.
43亿
4.3 billion.
我很有感触  我明白人民的感受
You know, I have feelings. And I feel for people that are out there...
巴巴布伊  巴巴布伊  你看
Baba Booey! Baba Booey! Yes. See.
他可能就是我的忠实粉丝
That's probably one of my satisfied customers right there.
我的天啊  太糟糕了
Oh, my God. Oh, my God. This is terrible.
你真的认为  一个商人可以经营这个城市
Do you really think a businessman can run the city?
在斯塔克斯手机公司
At Stacks Mobile,
我搭建了一个从不漏接电话的手机网络
I made a cell network that never drops a call.
作为一个市长  我创建的政府
As mayor, I'm gonna make a government
将从不落下一个市民
that never drops a citizen.
是啊  只要那些市民都住在市中心
Yeah, as long as those citizens live below 96th Street.
你要庆幸你还不能投票  政治家都是骗子
You're lucky you can't vote yet, mija. Politicians are all liars.
这两个的保质期要怎么改
What dates should I change these to?
牛奶改成一个星期  果汁改两个星期
One week for the milk. Two weeks for the juice.
你要多一些微笑  你只笑了4次
You need to smile more. You only smiled four times.
是吗  真的吗
Is that right? Really?
如果你多笑笑  选票会上涨23%
Voters respond 23% more favorably to full-teeth smiles.
那竖大拇指呢
Yeah. How about thumbs up, huh?
如果你竖一个大拇指的话  可以上涨16%
Sixteen percent better if you give them a single.
如果双手竖大拇指的话  可以上涨38%
Thirty-eight percent if you shoot them the double.
我怎么觉得  自己是在浪费时间呢
Why do I get the feeling like I'm wasting my time here?
我到底能不能赢
Am I gonna win, or not?
因为这简直就是浪费时间
'Cause this seems like a waste of time.
你请我就是为了赢得选票  你会赢的
You hired me to win. You're gonna win.
带上这个  为什么  我已经穿了
Put this on. Why? I'm already dressed.
你好吗  给
How you doing? Here.
我要给流浪汉做东西吃吗
Whoa, I gotta feed the hobos?
别说"流浪汉"  叫"游荡者"
Don't say "hobos." Say "bums."
由于某种原因  大家都认为
For some crazy reason, everybody thinks
你是个富有的杰出人物  不像普通人那么好相处
you're a rich elitist that can't relate to regular people.
于是  牛津大学的高才女  要告诉我怎么赢得选举
So, the girl from Oxford is trying to tell me how to keep it real.
我告诉你  你要是想赢得选举
I'm telling you if you want a chance at this,
你要记住你是从哪里来的
you're gonna have to remember where you came from.
好了吗  盖茨比
Okay, Gatsby?
用食物恭维他们  不过不是很多
Compliment them on the food, but not too much.
我不会吃的  你要吃这些食物
I ain't eating this food. You're gonna eat the food.
你要喜欢这些食物  但是不要爱上它们  明白吗
And you're gonna like it, but you're not gonna love it, okay?
我不想看起来像个拉皮条的
We don't want to seem like we're pandering.
我不吃流浪汉的食物  好了  很好
I don't eat hobo food. All right. That's good.
大家好  你们饿了吗
How we doing, folks? Starving?
你晚上睡得怎样
How do you sleep at night?
有丝绸床单  都还得吃安眠药
Silk sheets and Ambien.
快看看这些俊男靓女
Look at all these handsome faces!
给你  好了
There you go. All right.
给你  上帝保佑你
And here we go. God bless.
我猜你从来都不吃土豆泥  斯塔克斯先生
Bet you never had mashed potatoes, Mr. Stacks.
怎么可能
Are you kidding me?
我奶奶曾经是  皇后区最好的土豆泥厨师
Why, my grandmother made some of the best mashed potatoes in Queens.
我就是从那儿来的  出生和成长都在那
You know, that's where I'm from. Born and raised.
我一天当中  大部分时间都在操场上度过
On the playground's where I spent most of my days.
你看这个
And look at this.
没什么特别的  一点也不可怕  你看
It's not amazing, but it ain't terrible. Look at this.
噎到了
Went down the wrong pipe.
这太恶心了
This is disgusting.
太难吃了
Look, it's terrible.
天啊  你就像个小孩子
Oh, God. You're a child.
你们觉得刚刚进展如何
Well, how do you guys think that went?
纳什  你也看到了
Nash, you saw it.
要是你不在我手下做事  你会投我吗
Would you vote for me if you didn't work for me?
不会的  先生
No, sir.
谢谢你这么诚实  你被解雇了
Thank you for your honesty. You're fired.
速度真快
That didn't take long.
而且  新闻也发布出来了
And there are already parodies.
土豆泥  土豆泥
Mashed potatoes Mashed potatoes
土豆泥  皇后区的土豆泥
Mashed potatoes, mashed potatoes In Queens
这就是为什么中国会赢的原因  不是的
See, this is why China's winning. Not really.
也许这会因祸得福
Maybe this is a blessing in disguise.
因为这表明你可以做市长  但不表明你应该做市长
Just because you can run for mayor, doesn't mean that you should.
我们已经讨论过了  当市长的经历
We already discussed this is great for my profile.
对公司的成长很有帮助
It's going to grow the company.
再说了  这个城市需要我
Plus, the city needs me.
好吧  放松点  蝙蝠侠
All right. Take it easy, Batman.
你的所有员工  都是这么跟你说话的吗
You let all your employees talk to you like this?
那些让我赚几十亿的人可以这样
The ones that make me billions, I do.
你让我当上市长  你想怎么说都行
You make me mayor, you can say anything you want.
嘿
Hey!
不是吧  又来了
Oh, no. Not again.
那是  怎么回事
Nash. Why we stopping?
抱歉  斯塔克斯先生  我会修好的
Sorry, Mr. Stacks. I'll fix it.
下一个
Next!
我想看看我的资料  谢谢
I'd like to get my records please.
你要填表格  编号是4380
You'll need DOH form number 4380...
7-8.
还有43美元  55分
And $43 and... 55 cents.
还有父母或监护人的
And an application signed by a parent or a...
签名
Guardian. Bam.
都在这了
It's all there.
你打算就这样一直盯着我吗
Are you going to stare at me the whole time?
抱歉
Sorry.
下一个  你能帮我读一下吗  我太紧张了
Next! Can you read it? I'm too nervous.
"安妮·班尼特  被遗弃在26区外
"Annie Bennett. Abandoned outside 26th Precinct.
估计遗弃年龄为4岁
"Age estimate at time of abandonment, four years.
现处于家庭寄养  无其他信息"
"Placed in state foster care. No further data."
"无其他信息"  是什么意思
What does "no further data" mean?
意思是你的信息只有这么多  抱歉  亲爱的
That's all there is to know about you. Sorry, honey.
没关系  我会想办法的
It's okay. I'll figure it out.
The sun'II come out tomorrow
Bet your bottom dollar that tomorrow
There'II be sun
Just thinkin' about tomorrow
Clears away the cobwebs and the sorrow
'Til there's none
When I'm stuck with a day
That's gray, and lonely
I just stick out my chin and grin
And say, oh
快点  爸爸
Faster, Daddy!
The sun'II come out tomorrow
So you gotta hang on 'til tomorrow
Come what may
Tomorrow, tomorrow
I love you, tomorrow
You're always a day away!
When I'm stuck with a day
That's gray, and lonely
I just stick out my chin and grin
And say, oh
The sun'II come out tomorrow
So you gotta hang on 'til tomorrow
Come what may
Tomorrow, tomorrow
I love you, tomorrow
You're always a day away!
Tomorrow, tomorrow
I love you, tomorrow
You're always a day
Away!
抓住它  快抓住它
Get it! Get it!
快点  嘿
Come on! Hey!
扔点东西过去
Throw something at it!
扔罐头
Throw the can!
嘿  站住  别管闲事
Hey! Stop! Mind your own business!
怎么了
What's going on?
我不知道  我不是机修工
I don't know. I'm not a chemist.
这个引擎还在试验阶段
Jimmy Neutron here had me throw this experimental engine in.
这表明了他爱护环境
It shows that he cares about the environment.
这是他具有前瞻性的想法
You know, that he's forward-thinking.
太好了  有人来拍照了
Oh, great. Here they come with the pictures.
我们得让她走  这太奇怪了
We gotta distract her. Something whimsical.
我去找树叶
Let's get into a leaf fight!
女士
Ma'am.
好  我来叫车
Okay, okay. I'm gonna call a car.
嘿  我走路回去
Hey! I'm gonna go walk.
什么
What?
他要去哪里  我想一个人静一静
Where's he going? I wanna be alone.
我们没有时间了  我知道要怎么走
We don't really have time. I know how to walk down the street!
我把方位发给你
I'll text you directions!
不用
Don't need them.
这都是你的错  别激动
This is all your fault. Take it easy, pantsuit.
还有你  抱歉
And, you... I'm sorry.
嘿  斯塔克斯  你的手机话费快害死我了
Hey, Stacks! Your phone bill's killing me, bro!
抓住它  我说了  站住
Get it! I told you to stop!
再快点
Try to hit it!
别追它了
Leave it alone!
嘿
Hey!
好了  踢它  快踢它  住手
All right, kick it! Kick it! Stop!
别动它  看它多害怕
Leave it alone! See how scared it is!
别管
Leave it...
你还是管好自己吧  小鬼  你没事吧
Watch where you're going, kid! Are you okay?
我们快走  你差点就被压过去了
Let's get out of here! You could've got run over.
抱歉  别抱歉  你要小心点
Sorry. Don't be sorry. You be careful.
你为什么要跑  因为我赶时间
Why're you running? Gets me to places quicker.
小孩子  有细菌的小孩子
Little kids. Kids with germs.
图书馆怎么样
How was the library?
深受教育
Educational.
我也要教育一下你
Well, I have some more education for you.
我和检察员说  我不想再收养你了
I told the inspector I don't wanna foster you anymore.
下个星期  你就要成为别人的麻烦了
As of next week, you're somebody else's problem.
那他说了是谁吗
Did they say who?
那就不是谁了  而是什么
Not a who, sweetie. A what.
收留所
Group home.
好吧
Okay.
也许那样能教你怎么管住你的嘴
Maybe that'll teach you to stop running your mouth.
新手机有什么特点
So, where are we with our new phones?
我们的电池  待机时间超过150小时
Well, we've got the battery up to 150 hours.
那还不到一个星期
That's not a week.
我说了要待机一个星期的  格蕾丝  我还特地说过的
I said I need the charge to last a week, Grace. Specifically.
很不幸  目前  手机会烧伤人们的手
At the moment, unfortunately, the phone is burning up in people's hands.
什么
What?
这就是我想说的  妈妈  他跟我说  她
That's what I told Mom. And she says to me, she...
你烫到我了
You burned me!
别担心  她签了弃权声明
Don't worry. She signed a waiver.
你烫到我了
You burned me!
什么情况
What up, Guy-O?
你的支持率提升了5%
You're up. Five points in the polls.
真的吗  他们喜欢向流浪汉呕吐吗
Really? They liked that he vomited on a homeless man?
不是  格蕾丝
No, Grace.
他们喜欢他救了一个差点被货车撞到的小女孩
They liked the fact that he saved a little girl from getting hit by a van.
有人拍下来了  把他放在网上  来看看吧
Some guy recorded it, put it on the Internet. Check it out.
"我是个小女孩  没有看路
"I'm a little girl who doesn't see where I'm going.
你看  跌倒了
"Well, look!
未来的纽约市长  救了我的命"
I bumped into the future mayor of New York who just saved my life!"
这太棒了  威廉
This is fantastic, Will.
我告诉你  恕我直言  这是你有史以来
I'm telling you. It's the most human thing you've done
做的最人道的事  不足挂齿
this entire campaign, all due respect. None taken.
你怎么没告诉我  你救了一个小女孩  你什么也没说
You didn't tell me you saved a little girl. You didn't tell me anything.
就像蜘蛛侠一样
Like Batman.
听着  你要利用这一点
Hey, listen to me. You gotta capitalize on this.
那当然  你要请她过来吃饭
Of course we do. You invite her to lunch.
不行  看看她怎么样
No. See how she's doing.
拍几张照片  媒体就爱吃这一套
Snap a few pics. The press'II eat this up.
我们认识她吗  这才是最重要的
Do we know who she is? That's the best part.
她是黑人区收养的孩子
She's a foster kid from Harlem.
你听到我说什么了吗  她是孤儿  黑人区的
Did you hear what I said? Foster kid! Harlem!
你眼部的血管都鼓起来了
Your undereye vein is bulging.
我会找到她的  不要  我让格蕾丝去找她
I'm gonna go get her. No. I'm gonna let Grace go get her.
什么  为什么  什么  这个主意太糟糕了
What? Why? What? That's a terrible idea!
那你想让这个人
Do you actually want 5-hour Energy to go over there
过去吓坏这个小女孩吗
and scare this little child?
我都不知道是怎么回事  格蕾丝  拜托
I don't even know what this is about. Grace, please.
就当为了我  格蕾丝
For me, Grace. Please.
谢谢  威廉  让我去黑人区吧
Thank you. Will, let me go to Harlem.
拜托  别让她去  去黑人区  你会被爆菊的
Please. Don't send her. They will whoop your ass in Harlem.
别关掉  谢谢
Don't shut me off. Thank you.
别关掉
Don't shut me off!
你好
Yeah.
是科琳·汉尼根吗
Is that Colleen Hannigan?
我想进去和你谈谈  你照顾的一个小孩的情况
I was wanting to talk to you about a girl in your care.
安妮
Annie.
是威廉·斯塔克斯叫我来的  他想请安妮共进午餐
I work for William Stacks and he would love to take Annie out for lunch.
为什么
Why?
他们昨天撞到了  她没跟你说吗
They ran into each other yesterday. She didn't tell you?
没有
No.
昨天晚上  我们没有时间好好谈话
We didn't have a chance to have our girl-talk jawbone last night.
安妮
Annie!
你是说他撞到她了
So you said he ran into her?
因为我注意到她的脖子  好像有点僵硬
'Cause I noticed that her neck did seem a little whiplash-y.
我们非常乐意  捐助你选的机构
We are happy to make a donation to the charity of your choice.
天啊  那选择太多了
Gosh! There's so many to choose from.
是的  比如  拯救鲸鱼机构
There is. Let's see, Save the Whales, of course.
净水组织  没有干净的水  鲸鱼怎么生存
And Clean Water, but you can't have whales without water.
天啊  你知道吗
Gosh. You know what?
你把现金给我就可以了  我来帮你分配
Just make it out to "cash." I'll divvy it up.
太好了  安妮
Perfect. Annie!
她就像个天使
You know, she's such an angel.
可遇而不可求  我们把她当亲生女儿看待
We don't inherit the Earth, we borrow it from our children.
你们感情真好
It's a lovely sentiment.
她来了
There she is.
嗨  安妮  我是格蕾丝
Hi, Annie. I'm Grace.
我是斯塔克斯先生的下属  就是昨天撞你的那位先生
I work for Mr. Stacks, the gentleman that you ran into yesterday.
他想请你共进午餐
He'd like to invite you to lunch.
我保证  不会耽误你太多时间的
I promise we won't keep you long.
你让我待多久都可以
You can keep me as long as you want.
不会吧  这是真的吗
No way! Is this for real?
这辆车跟地铁一样大  你太幸运了
This car's as big as a subway! You're so lucky!
真不可思议
It's incredible.
我的天啊  我也想上车  我的天啊
Oh, my gosh. I want that! Oh, my gosh!
想吃什么都可以
Help yourself to whatever you want.
不是吧  真的吗
No way. Really?
当然
Sure.
给我这个  我要这个  噢  我的天啊
Give me this! Give me this! I want this! Oh, my God!
我要那个  我要那个  太过瘾了  我的天啊
I want that one! I want that! This is crazy! My God!
小孩这么喜欢吃糖啊
Kids love candy, huh?
嘿  安妮  或许我应该跟你一起去
Hey, Annie! Maybe I should come with you
确保一切进行的更顺利  对吧
and make sure that everything's USDA Grade A awesome, huh?
我可以的  谢谢
I'm good. Thanks.
再见  安妮
Bye, Annie!
再见  再见
Bye! Later.
谢谢  我的天啊
Thanks! Oh, my gosh.
嘿  美女
Hey, gorgeous!
有个出名的孩子  感觉如何
How does it feel to have a famous kid?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
这是安妮
It's Annie!
你的安妮
Your Annie!
令晚想和我约会吗  我买了跳舞的裤子
Hey, you wanna go out tonight? I got my dance pants on.
我的人格还没这么低
I haven't hit that rock bottom yet.
我就喜欢你这么对我说话
I love it when you throw me shade!
给  卢  没事  她会喜欢我的
Here, Lou. It's okay. She likes me.
天啊  这太好吃了
Oh, my God, this is so good.
斯塔克斯先生  想和你合影  可以吗
Mr. Stacks would like to take some pictures with you, if that's all right.
应该可以  为什么  人们想知道你没事
I guess so. Why? People wanna know that you're okay.
哪些人  所有看到新闻的人
What people? Everybody who saw that.
我的头发蓬的好大
My hair's gigantic.
你想收听什么节目都可以  我可以听一下脱口秀吗
We can listen to whatever you like. Can you put on talk radio?
你确定不想听音乐吗
Are you sure you don't wanna listen to music?
我喜欢听脱口秀  可以让我平静
I love talk radio. It calms me.
我也是  我小时候超爱听
So do I. I loved it when I was a little girl.
我曾经认为  他们都是我的朋友
I used to think that they were all my friends.
抱歉  那听起来太伤感了
Sorry, that sounded very sad. Sorry.
我有很多朋友  不用担心我
I have a lot of friends, so don't worry about me.
我的工作很忙  真的  我本来可以交更多朋友的
I mean, so I work a lot. I do. And I could have some more friends.
但是你真正需要的朋友  又有几个呢
But how many friends do you really need?
有时我父母问起我
I mean, if you were my parents asking me,
"你过得充实  幸福吗  格蕾丝"
"Are you fulfilled and are you happy, Grace?"
这完全跑题了
That's a whole different conversation, right?
我们还是不说这个了
But we're not having that conversation.
老实说  你没这个资格  问我朋友多不多  所以
And, frankly, it's really not your position to ask me that at all. So...
好吧
Okay.
她来了  我们的小孤儿安妮
There she is. Our own Little Orphan Annie.
是收养的孩子
Foster kid.
她来了
She's here.
嘿  就是她  对吧  好了  我们开始吧
Hey, this is the one, right? All right. Let's get this.
等一下
Slow your roll.
你说  我们可以先吃饭吗  坐了很长时间的车
Excuse me? Can we eat first? It was a long drive.
好  快去
Yeah, yeah. Go, go.
好的  当然  我们先吃  我们有的是时间拍照
Yeah, yeah, sure. Let's eat. We got time for that.
好了
All right.
你昨天撞了我后  有什么感受
So, how are you feeling from yesterday?
别演戏了
So, what's the hustle?
你怎么这么想  我没有演戏
What makes you think there's a hustle? There's no hustle.
快  快
Come on, come on.
我10岁了  我不是傻瓜
I'm 10. I'm not an idiot.
我从来没说你是
I never said you were...
什么傻瓜  或10岁
an idiot. Or 10.
事实是  我还不知道你多大
Truth of the matter is, I don't know how old you are.
10岁  好  我们知道  你不是傻瓜
Ten. Well, now we know that you're not an idiot.
但是还有很多人
But there are a lot of people out there
看了我救你的照片
that are and when they saw that photo of us,
他们都觉得  我会是个好的市长
they thought that I would make a great mayor.
为什么
Why?
为什么  因为我是
Why? Because I'm a...
我是个富人  我救了一个孤儿
I'm a rich guy. I saved an orphan.
我不是孤儿  我是被收养的孩子
I'm not an orphan, I'm a foster kid.
而且你并没有救我
And you didn't save me.
我没有救你  不是我把你从火车前抱起来的吗
I didn't save you? I didn't just push you out of the way of a van?
要不我把那辆车找回来  完成他所做的
Why don't I call that van back and have him finish up what he...
你知道吗
You know what?
越多人看到我们在一起  我的竞选就越有可能
The more we're seen together, the better it is for my campaign.
等下  市长就是这么被选出来的吗
Wait. That's how a mayor gets elected?
是的  很出入意料吧
Yes. lnsane, isn't it?
要是我跟你一起住的话  那你不是可以当总统了
I bet if I moved in with you, you'd become president.
跟我一起住
Move in with me?
这不是什么派对
This is not that kind of party.
好了  好了
That's it. That's it. That's it.
我觉得他有话想跟你说
I think he wants to tell you something.
其实这个主意不错  安妮搬过来跟你一起住
Actually, that's not a bad idea. Annie coming to live with you.
什么  什么
What? What?
据我所知  你住的地方很拥挤
From what I understand, it's very crowded where you live.
你想不想住一个宽阔的地方  你可能会喜欢的地方
How'd you like some more space? Is that something that you might like?
跟一个世界首富一起住
Living with the richest guy in the world?
这个我喜欢
Yeah, that's something I might like.
太好了  你在搞什么鬼
Great. Perfect. Guy. What are you talking about?
听我说  只要住几周就行了
Listen to me. It'll only be for a few weeks.
然后她就可以回去了
Then she'll go back to wherever she came from.
领养一个孩子  马上可以赢得15%的选票
Taking in a foster kid, that's an automatic 15 point jump in the polls.
我保证  一你要我扮演奶爸
Guaranteed. You want me to play Daddy?
很简单的  我只需要一日三餐和一张床
It's easy. All I need is a bed and meals.
其他你什么都不用管
You don't have to do anything else.
而且一周你还可以拿到157美元
And you get $157 a week.
我像那种需要157美元一周的人吗
Do I look like I need $157 a week?
每个人都不会拒绝一周157美元的
Everybody needs an extra $157 a week.
你不会真的想这样吧
You're not really thinking about doing this?
你想跟我合影  对吧
You want photos, right?
我相信要合影  还有很多更简单的办法
I'm sure there's easier ways to get photos.
那绝对不是跟我拍
Not with me in them.
微笑
Smile.
斯塔克斯先生
Mr. Stacks!
你真的想这样吗  没错  我要每个人都知道
Are you really doing this? Yeah, won't even know she's there.
就像养了一只乌龟一样  她可不是省油的灯
It's like having a turtle. I wonder if she has her shots.
午餐怎么样  你叫什么名字
How was your lunch? What's your name?
她叫安妮  她要过来跟斯塔克斯先生住一段时间
Her name is Annie, and she'll be staying with Mr. Stacks for awhile.
他打算领养你吗
He's going to adopt you?
没有  我有父母  这只是暂时的  如果通过批准的话
No, no, no. I have parents. This is just temporary. If he gets approved.
现在怎么办  下一个
What now? Next.
我需要申请临时监护人
I need a temporary guardian approval, please.
这需要6周的时间  还要填写表格
There is a six-week waiting period and you need form NYS 84-...
亲爱的上帝
Sweet Lord.
嗨
Hi.
我通常都不做实地考察的
You know, I don't normally do the site visits,
但是看你这么喜欢这个可爱的安妮
but I've taken such a liking to young Annie.
有时候我会忘记自己  为什么要这么做
I forget sometimes, you know, why I got into this.
就是为了存档
It's for my files.
监护人是否"有能力提供一个合适的住所"
So, does the guardian have "adequate income to provide basic shelter"?
我只是按流程办事
I'm just gonna go ahead and check that box.
请进
Come on in.
...每股95美元的现金和股票
...about $95 per share in cash and stock.
这绝对是个爆炸性的新闻...
...detonated an explosive while fire...
哇  是啊  哇
Whoa. Oh, yeah, whoa.
嘿  这里有临时监护人伙伴吗
Hey, is there a co-temporary guardian?
没有  那你想要找一个临时监护人伙伴呜
No. Would you like a co-temporary guardian?
我带他们四处转转吧  你专心工作
Why don't I take these guys on a tour, and you can get back to work.
这个主意不错
Best idea of the day.
我跟你一起去
I'll come with you.
威廉  威廉
Will. Will, Will!
好了  国家要求  房屋至少有
Okay, so the state says that you must have at least
一处水源
one water source in...
没问题
Check.
还有一个窗户  也没问题
And a window that's... Okay.
10个人至少要有一张椅子
And then at least one chair per 10 persons.
我觉得这个星际飞船应该算了  我再看看
And I think the Starship Enterprise is gonna count. I'm gonna check that box.
这是怎么做到的
How does it do this?
这是智能家居
It's a smart house.
它能够识别你的声音  并作出相应调整
So, it recognizes your voice and then adjusts itself accordingly.
就像一个朋友
It's like a friend.
我把它当作朋友
I consider it a friend.
不过我有真正的朋友  他们不是机器人哦
But I have real friends that aren't robots.
我们还是别谈这个话题了
Let's forget this conversation
我们继续先前的话题  重头开始
and the previous conversation and start afresh.
明白吗  太好了
Got that? Great.
现在我要录下你的声音  安妮  你会被记录到系统中
I'm gonna record your voice now, Annie, and it'll be in the system.
对着这个说几句话
So, just say something into this.
我要说什么  任何事都可以
What should I say? Anything.
我觉得我会喜欢这里的
I think I'm gonna like it here.
成功了
Got it.
太好了  这都听你的了
Great. It's all yours.
你试试看  我等下再过来
Have a go. And I'll be back.
女士
Ma'am?
抱歉  你不能进去
Excuse me. You are not allowed to go in there.
这里太棒了  这些是卤素灯泡吗
This is very nice. Are those halogen bulbs?
女士  这个水槽比我家还大
Ma'am. This sink is bigger than my entire country.
我觉得我会喜欢这里的
I think I'm gonna like it here.
I think I'm gonna like it
我确定我会喜欢这里的
I'm sure I'm gonna like it
我觉得我会喜欢这里的
I think I'm gonna like it here
那么  想好了就来吧
So, think it and it shall appear
我觉得我会喜欢这里的
I think I'm gonna like it here
因为它知道我想看什么
Because it knows just what you wanna see
等等  我觉得它想来见我
Wait, I think it and it comes to me?
这儿有架大钢琴可以弹
Here's something grand for you to play
等下  我昨天还没有这些的
Wait, I couldn't do that yesterday
我觉得我会喜欢这里的
I think I'm gonna like it here
想不喜欢都难  亲爱的
It's very hard not to, my dear
是的  我觉得我会喜欢这里的
Yes, yes, I think I'm gonna like it here Yes,
yes, I think I'm gonna like it here
我觉得我会喜欢这里的  我觉得我会喜欢这里的
Think I'm gonna like it here Think I'm gonna like it here
我觉得我会喜欢这里的
I think I'm gonna like it here
是的  我觉得我会喜欢这里的
Yes, yes, I think I'm gonna like it here Yes,
yes, I think I'm gonna like it here
我觉得我会喜欢这里的  我觉得我会喜欢这里的
Think I'm gonna like it here Think I'm gonna like it here
看
Look!
是自动温控泳池
It knows the temp you're comfy in.
太棒了  能教我游泳吗
That's great. Can it teach me to swim?
我们去请个教练  别怕
We'll get a coach, no need to fear.
我觉得我会喜欢这里的
I think I'm gonna like it here
水好冷
The water's cold!
曾经的梦
Everything you've ever dreamed
尽在指尖
Is at your fingertips
如果有你没梦到的
And if you haven't dreamed it yet
把它添入愿望清单
Add it to your wish list
这是斯塔克斯先生的房间吗
Is this Mr. Stacks' room?
不  安妮  这是你的房间
No, Annie, this is your room.
我的天啊
Sweet Lord.
我觉得我会喜欢的
I think I'm gonna like it
I know I'm gonna like it
我知道你会喜欢的
I know you're gonna like it
你肯定会喜欢的
Damn right, you're gonna like it
我觉得我会喜欢这的
I think I'm gonna like it here!
是的  我觉得我会喜欢的
Yes, yes, I think I'm gonna like it here Yes,
yes, I think I'm gonna like it here
我觉得我会喜欢的  我觉得我会喜欢的
Think I'm gonna like it here Think I'm gonna like it here
我觉得我会喜欢的
I think I'm gonna like it here
是的  我觉得我会喜欢的
Yes, yes, I think I'm gonna like it here Yes,
yes, I think I'm gonna like it here
我觉得我会喜欢的  我觉得我会喜欢的
Think I'm gonna like it here Think I'm gonna like it here
是的  是的
Yes, yes!
衣橱超级大  大到我还以为是客厅
The closet was so big, I thought it was the living room.
真的吗  那客厅有多大
Really? How big was the living room?
就像康涅狄格州那么大  我的天啊
I thought it was Connecticut. Oh, my gosh.
他人好吗  挺好的
Is he nice? I think so.
只是他自己还不知道这点
He just doesn't know it yet.
我们会想你的  安妮
We're gonna miss you, Annie.
我才不会想你  这里终于清净了
I'm not. Finally can get a little space in here.
当你们想我了  你们都可以给我打电话
Well, whenever you miss me, all you gotta do is call.
什么  不会吧
Bam, bam. What? Are you serious?
斯塔克斯手机
Bam. Stacks phones?
你也有份  佩珀  我知道你会想我的
Even one for you, Pepper. I know you're gonna miss me. Bam.
没有盖子啊  垃圾
No case, huh? This is janky.
嘿  威廉·斯塔克斯先生
Hey, Mr. Will Stacks.
我是不是应该叫你"准市长"
Or should I say Soon-To-Be-Mr.Mayor?
不用  谢谢  我在等人
No, thank you. We're just waiting on someone.
我可没想找什么临时伙伴
I'm not looking for temporary companionship.
不是嫌弃你
Not judging you.
上帝为我们每个人指明了道路
God has a path for us all.
你的道路就是离这车远一点  什么
Your path should be away from the car. What?
女士  麻烦离车远点
Ma'am, wanna move away from the car, please?
你竟敢
How dare you...
不是吧  你想喷我
Oh, really, you're gonna spray me?
你以为你比我好吗
You think you're better than me?
是吗  你以为你比我好吗
Is that what it is? You think you're better than me?
没错  我确实比你好
I do. I do think I'm better than you.
嘿  汉尼根小姐  什么事
Hey, Miss Hannigan. What?
我只想感谢你为我付出的一切
I just wanna thank you for everything you've done for me.
你以为你的生活就像童话吗
You think your life is a fairy tale?
根本就没有"从此过上了幸福的生活"
There is no happily ever after.
幸福就像昙花一现
And the worst thing is to get a little taste of something good
绝对不会持久的
'cause it never lasts.
在那之后  你的生活就不再是
And then all you can taste from then on out is
那么幸福了
not that taste.
她想说什么  让她说就好了  记住没
Just let her talk when she gets like this, remember?
闭嘴
Shut up!
科琳·汉尼根  上我微博上赞我
Colleen Hannigan! H-bomb! Like me on Facebook!
我不喜欢黑人区的人  我为什么要去微博上赞你
I don't like you in Harlem. Why would I like you on Facebook?
快进去  小鬼们
Come on, rats, let's go!
快进去  再见  安妮
Inside! Bye, Annie.
再见
Bye.
怎么回事  不用担心
What was that? Don't worry about it.
好了  纳什  我们走吧
All right, Nash, we can take off.
走不了  前面有辆卡车
I can't, there's a truck.
注意你的左边  纳什  注意你的左边  淡定
Bogey on your left, Nash, bogey on your left. Steady.
不用  谢谢  我们不找什么伙伴
No, thank you. I'm not looking for companionship.
这附近的人是怎么了  不是的  他是卢
What is it with this neighborhood? No, that's Lou.
你认识她  他是男的
You know her name? It's a he.
嘿  姑娘  嘿  我有东西要送给你
Hey, girl. Hey. I got you something.
不用  谢谢  那都是坑人的东西
No, thanks. Those things are evil.
它会窃取你的私人信息
They steal your private information
这样的大企业就可以监控你  然后榨干你的灵魂
so that big business can spy on you and crush your soul.
真的吗
Really?
不过我还是替你感到高兴
I'm happy for you though, mija.
能够离开这里  保重  再见  卢
Getting off the block. Take care. Bye, Lou.
对她好点  斯塔克斯先生
Stay warm, Mr. Stacks.
抱歉  他只是不太喜欢你而已
Sorry. He just doesn't like you.
很多人不喜欢我  所以我才这么做
A lot of people don't like me. That's why we're doing this.
别担心  我有一张讨人喜欢的脸
Don't worry, I got a game face.
我们再拍些合影吧
Let's take some photos.
我的对手要有两个原因
My opponent wants to be mayor for two reasons.
第一  满足他的自大心理  第二  增加商业利益
To feed his ego, and bolster his business interests.
他现在却领养了一个女孩儿  拜托
And now he coincidentally takes in a foster kid? Come on.
别把我当傻子
Don't pee in my ear and tell me it's hot rain.
你觉得领养安妮  是一项政治谋划
Are you saying Annie is a political move?
我很好奇  他连狗都没养过
I'm surprised he hasn't gotten a dog yet.
我真的可以养一只吗
Are you sure I can have one?
不行  可以
No. Yes.
小孩喜欢狗  拜托
Look, kids love dogs. Come on,
在街上看到狗  他们都会
they see them on the street and they all go...
我说的对吗  狗狗
Am I right? Hello.
女人也是一样  狗狗
You know, women do the same thing. Hello.
你好啊
Hello.
那只怎么样
What about that one?
它很早就被遗弃了  它需要多一点关爱
She was separated from her pack too early. She just needs a little love.
别选那只狗  它在舔自己的屁股
Don't pick that one, it's licking its own hoo-hah.
嘿  美女  我们又见面了
Hey, girl, we found each other.
我再也不会丢弃你了  我保证
I'll never leave you again, I promise.
安妮  你打算给它取什么名字
Annie, what are you gonna name it?
它就像龙卷风一样
She's like a hurricane.
桑迪  它叫桑迪
Sandy. Her name's gonna be Sandy.
我就说嘛
I told you.
安妮  我们可以合个影吗  当然
Annie, will you take a picture with us? Sure.
谢谢安妮
Thanks, Annie.
她很喜欢你
She really likes you.
看
Look.
嘿
Hey.
有事吗
Something wrong?
睡不着  这里太安静了
Couldn't sleep. So quiet up here.
你在干什么  我在工作
What you doing? I'm working.
这么晚了还工作  习惯了
This late? Always.
那你什么时候可以玩  这就是在玩
When do you have fun? This is fun.
我虽然没去过迪士尼乐园
I haven't been to Disneyland,
但是我觉得他们那儿  应该没有你这种娱乐项目
but I don't think they have a paperwork ride.
要是你饿了  这儿有很多吃的  不要在这儿吃
Look, if you're hungry, there's not a lot of food here. Only takeout.
冰箱
Fridge.
赞
Cool.
随便拿
Knock yourself out.
你没有厨师吗  或者很多仆人
You don't have a cook? Or like a million servants?
没有  我喜欢一个人生活
Nope, I don't. I like to be alone.
那你要这么大的地方干什么
So why do you need all this space?
因为我喜欢在大的地方  一个人生活
'Cause I like to be alone with a lot of space.
人们以为彼此相互在一起
Look, I think people surround themselves with other people
就能感受到爱  但我不这么认为
just so they can feel loved. I don't believe in that.
我相信真正爱你的人  是因为你有钱
I believe the people that actually love you, you can count them on one hand.
你知道你在握拳吗
You know you're making a fist.
随便啦
Whatever.
你的下属去哪儿
Where are your people?
哇  你的间题还真多  小鬼  我的下属都不在这里
Wow, you ask a lot of questions, little one. My people aren't around.
你想招新人吗  不想
You don't want new ones? I'm good.
知道吗  我饿了
You know what? I am hungry.
不管你有什么食材  我都会做  选5种食材吧
I can make a meal out of anything. Pick five ingredients.
我才不选  拜托  很有意思的
I don't want to. Come on, this'll be fun.
安妮  我没时间  不工作  真的很有趣的
Annie, listen, I don't have time... Not work, but almost as fun.
好吧  意大利螺旋粉  意大利烟肉  牛排  石榴
All right. Fusilli, pancetta, steak, pomegranate,
松露番茄干
truffle, sun-dried tomatoes.
我只听过其中两种  上网搜吧
I've only heard of two of those things. Google it.
好了  你的锅碗瓢盆在哪儿  锅碗瓢盆
Okay, where are your pots and pans? Pots and pans.
我知道
I know.
赞  赞
Cool. Cool.
放点这个
Put some in there.
放点胡萝卜  你不用切一下胡萝卜吗
Put in some carrot? You're not gonna chop that carrot?
你讨厌乳糖吗
You lactose-intolerant?
我讨厌小孩
I'm kid-intolerant.
你胆固醇高吗  现在挺好的
How's your cholesterol? It's good right now.
我下楼去拿些食材  马上回来
I'm gonna go downstairs and get some supplies. See you later.
我买了橙子回来了
Orange you glad I'm back?
第6种食材  是我开玩笑的
The sixth ingredient is my jokes.
上菜了
Order up.
我们真的要这样吗  干杯
Are we really doing this? Cheers.
你不是吧
You gotta be kidding me.
抱歉  太难吃了
Sorry, it's gross.
但你得学会控制呕吐  你又不是骆驼
But you gotta learn to stop spitting. You're not a camel.
盖伊有个疯狂的想法
Guy has this crazy idea
要我带你明晚去看电影首映
that I should take you to a movie premiere tomorrow night.
电影首映
A movie premiere?
是的
Yes.
我可以带我朋友去吗  那不是更麻烦了
Can I bring my friends? There's more of you?
可以拍更多照片  咔擦
More photos. Click, click.
好吧  多拍点照片
All right. More photos.
多拍点照片
More photos.
比刚刚更难吃了  是啊
It's worse the second time. Yeah.
这样就像双层床了
This is kind of like a bunk bed.
早上好  安妮  早上好  纳什
Morning, Annie. Good morning, Nash.
我知道这听起来很疯狂
I know this sounds crazy,
但是你们真的会  窃取别人手机的隐私吗
but do you guys spy on people with your phones?
为什么这么问
Why?
我想找一些人
I really need to find some people.
跟我来
Come with me.
快点  就快到了  这就是
Come on, you got it. There you go.
斯塔克斯手机的控制中心
Stacks Mobile Control Center.
我们可以追踪每通电话  每份数据传输
We can trace every call, every data transmission
这已经有20年了
made on every carrier over the past 20 years.
哇
Whoa.
人们不用害怕政府
People shouldn't be scared of governments.
他们应该害怕手机公司
They should be scared of cell phone companies.
查一下"班尼特"  正在检查
Check for Bennett. Checking.
有很多班尼特
That's a lot of Bennetts.
你能倒回到6年前吗
Can you please go back six years?
在26区附近
Around the 26th Precinct.
那得花点时间  不过可以查到的
It'll take a bit, but we'll let you know.
谢谢
Thanks.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
汉尼根有没有阻止你们
Did Hannigan catch you?
没有  她晕倒了
No, she's passed out.
她知道后就晕了
Things that make you go glug-glug.
斯塔克斯先生  你穿得是什么品牌
Mr. Stacks, who are you wearing?
阿玛尼
Armani.
安妮  你穿得是什么
Annie, who are you wearing?
这件是我朋友  伊莎贝拉的
This is my friend lsabella's,
这件好像是在哪找来的
and this I think I found somewhere.
安妮  你觉得  今天早上的法式吐司怎么样
Annie, how'd you like the French toast you had for breakfast this morning?
等下  你怎么知道
Wait. How'd you know that?
你发微博了@真实安妮
You tweeted it. @annie4realz
我帮你开了微博账号  目前为止  有130万粉丝
I started you a Twitter account. 1 .3 million followers so far.
你看到了吗"真实"
You get it? "4realz."
因为她是真实的
Because she's "for reals."
好了  你明白了吧
All right. You get it, right?
嘿  斯塔克斯手机  绝不漏接电话
Hey! Stacks Phones! Never drop a call.
记得给我投票
And vote for me, too.
"事出都是有因的"
Things happen for a reason.
"听说那小子每天晚上都不回家  而去月球上"
Says the boy who doesn't have to go home to the moon every night.
"那就别去"
Then don't go.
"你知道这并不是我的选择"
You know it's not my choice.
这到底在演什么
What the hell is happening?
她的月球眼泪流出来了  我知道
Her moon tears are running out. Of course they are.
那我要做决定了
Then I'll make it my choice.
你真的感动了
Did you just grab yourself?
"你的手机在震动"
You're buzzing.
"是你的手机"
It's your phone.
嘿  那是我们的手机
Hey, it's one of our phones.
时间到了
It's time.
那可花了50万美元  什么
That cost us $500,000. What?
植入广告
Product placement.
这就是电影行业的存在原因
It's the only thing that's keeping the movie business afloat.
"执行命令  然后回到女王国"
Execute your orders and return to the queendom.
"等你成功了  你的母亲就会被释放"
You succeed, and your mother will be set free.
"要是没有..."
If not...
"我们已经做到了"
We are ready down there.
"一旦月亮落下  我们就开始攻击"
Once the moon sets, we will attack.
"谢谢  萨卡纳"
Thanks, Sakana.
发生什么事了
What is going on?
她说要攻击月球  但我记得  他们已经攻击过了
The fish are going to attack the moon. But they should attack already.
不然凯尔和莎佛朗  就没时间
There's not gonna be enough time for Kyle and Saffron
逃离月亮怪了
to get away from the Luna Monsters.
攻击  萨卡纳  快攻击
Attack, Sakana, attack!
安静
Quiet.
萨卡纳  萨卡纳
Sakana, Sakana!
萨卡纳
Sakana!
坐下
Sit down.
我真不敢相信  萨卡纳竟然告诉他们了
I can't believe Sakana told on them.
那当然  你不会相信美人鱼的
Of course you can. You can't trust the fish people.
沃拉克警告过他们了
Gwarklark warned them.
我觉得她故意吓唬他们
I think she was bluffing.
不是  那只是个预示  说明还有下一部
Nah, it was a warning. They come back in the next movie.
还有下一部  还有4部
There's a next movie? There're four more.
闭嘴
Shut up!
哇  太赞了
Whoa! Cool!
我得回去工作了
I gotta get back to work.
你不留下来参加聚会吗
You can't stay for the party?
不能  我已经有两个小时没工作了
No. I haven't worked in two hours
我的下属肯定会以为我死了
and three of my men think I'm dead.
我还活着
I'm alive.
你已经工作的够多了
You've worked enough.
如果你的事业再高一点  就要撞到太阳了
If your building gets any taller it's gonna hit the sun.
你说服别人的方式真是奇怪
You got this crazy way of turning a no into a yes.
你是怎么做到的
How do you do that?
我觉得人们说"不"  的时候  他们只是害怕说"好"
I think when people say no, they're just really scared of saying yes.
好吧  我并不害怕  不行
Well, I'm not scared. No!
求你了  不行
Please! No!
求你了  好
Please. Yes.
太好了  走吧
Yes! Come on!
我不知道
Listen. I don't know.
好吧  太过瘾了
Well, okay. This is amazing.
斯塔克斯先生  威廉
Mr. Stacks! Will!
你竟然在这里待了这么久
I can't believe how long you've been here.
比赛我们就要迟到了
We're gonna be late for the Jets-Giants game.
你还要在仪式上扔硬币
You're doing the ceremonial coin flip.
还有一点  这两支队伍都是纽约的
And remember, they're both New York teams,
去还是不去  一样可以高兴或伤心的
so, heads or tails, you gotta be equally happy and sad.
你说得对
You're right.
你快去吧  我陪这些孩子
You go, I'll stay here with the kids.
你确定  是的
You sure? Yeah.
好了  快走吧
All right, come on, let's go.
怎么回事
What is that?
看  泰西
Look, Tessie!
我们可以再去一个地方吗
Can we make one more stop?
可以  别吵醒汉尼根了
Sure. Don't wake up Hannigan.
再见  再见  小美女们
Bye! Bye, girls!
你每周五都会来这里吗
You come here every Friday?
只有这天  他们才卖油煎酥饼
It's the only day they serve cannoli.
你只知道这一点吗
And that's all you've got to go on?
你还记得他们长什么样子吗
Do you think you'll remember what they look like?
我觉得我还记得
I think I'll just know.
你们怎么还没睡觉
What are you doing still up?
你们从哪儿拿的这些东西
Where did you get all of this stuff?
从哪儿拿的  从哪儿拿的
Where'd you get it? Where'd you get it?
我们和安妮去看电影了  我们还吃了糖果  喝了汽水
We went with Annie to the movies, and we got candy and soda,
我们还溜冰了  斯塔克斯先生太好了
and we went ice skating, and Mr. Stacks is so cool,
我还买了鱼人耳环
and I got fish earrings.
说得好  泰西
Nice, Tessie.
我忍不住这个秘密了  我买了鱼人耳环
I can't keep a secret. I got fish earrings.
包起来  送回去
Pack it up. It's going back.
为什么  因为这不是你们应得的
Why? Because you don't deserve it.
这就是我们应得的  是我们朋友给我们的
Yes, we do. It's from our friend.
她不是你们的朋友  斯塔克斯先生也不是
She's not your friend. And neither is Mr. Stacks.
他们都只是一群寄生虫  吸取你们的心血
They're all just a bunch of parasites who suck the life out of you
等你不再优秀了  他们会寻找新的目标
and move on once you're not the shiny new object in the Factory anymore.
你真讨厌
You're being mean.
我在教育你们
I'm being educational!
快收起来  你们太荒唐了
Now pack it up! You look ridiculous.
我没有摔倒
I didn't fall.
妈妈
Mama.
小女孩儿  小女孩儿
Little girls, little girls
她们随处可见
Everywhere I turn I can see them
小女孩儿  小女孩儿
Little girls, little girls
不管白天黑夜  不管吃饭睡觉  都能感受到她们
Night and day I eat, sleep and breathe them
快滚开
Get out of here!
我不该在这儿的
I should be anywhere but here
私人飞机  舞台或者音乐电视
Private planes, on the stage or MTV
在电视里的舞台上表演
But I find myself here at the snot house
小鞋子  小袜子
Little shoes, little socks
请杀了我吧  我说真的  杀了我吧
Please kill me. I'm serious, please kill me.
我没有唱歌  我在请求
I'm not singing, I'm asking.
我跟这些兔崽子  关在笼子里  我从缝隙里偷偷溜过
Locked in a cage with all the rats I've slipped through the cracks
现在我卡在缝隙中  找不到回去的路
And now I'm stuck with the scraps And I can't seem to find my way back
放我出去  放我出去
Get me out, get me out of here
放她出去
Oh, get her out
这些年来  我已经准备好当明星了
I'm ready for stardom after all these years
我受够了这些小女孩
I'm done with little girls
我想成为世上的重要人物
I wanna be someone in this world
小女孩儿  小女孩儿
Little girls, little girls
她们无处不在
Everywhere I turn I can see them
小女孩儿  小女孩儿
Little girls, little girls
不管白天黑夜  不管吃饭睡觉  都能感受到她们
Night and day I eat, sleep and breathe them
快滚开
Get out of here!
我和这些兔崽子  关在这里  我从缝隙里偷偷溜过
Locked in a cage with all the rats I've slipped through the cracks
现在我被卡在缝隙中  找不到回去的路
And now I'm stuck with the scraps And I can't seem to find my way back
放我出去  放我出去
Oh, get me out, get me out of here
救救我吧
Oh, throw me a rope
这些年  我已经准备好当明星了
I'm ready for stardom after all these years
我受够了这些小女孩儿
I'm done with little girls
我想成为世上的重要人物
I wanna be someone in this world
小女孩儿  小女孩儿
Little girls, little girls
我的天啊  天籁之音
Oh, my God. That was beautiful.
声音跟人一样美
Your voice matches your beauty.
听起来就像教堂的钟声
You sound like a church bell,
如果特别喜欢一个漂亮女人的话
if it was stuck on top of a beautiful woman,
或者如果一个漂亮女人在教堂的钟声里
or if a beautiful woman was inside a church bell.
并不是说你像教堂的钟  我不是这个意思
Not that you look like a church bell. That's not what I'm saying.
如果你是教堂的钟  我一定会每天去教堂的
If you looked like a church bell, I'd go to church every day.
什么
What?
我给你买了一件T恤  你会喜欢的
I got you a T-shirt, and you're gonna love it.
嘿  你准备好了吗  给
Here, you ready? Here.
怎么了
What...
你不喜欢这个颜色吗  还是不合尺寸  我店里还有很多
It's not your color? Not your size. I got more in the store.
你知道我在说什么的  教堂钟声
You know what I'm talking about, the church bell, right?
油煎酥饼  给你的美女朋友
Cannoli. One for your pretty friend.
谢谢
Thank you.
抱歉  孩子  没事
Sorry, kid. It's okay.
你可不可以  别告诉斯塔克斯吗  我不想麻烦他
Can you not tell Mr. Stacks about this? I don't want to bother him with it.
好的
Sure.
他把他的一生  无私的奉献给了纽约
He's worked selflessly his entire life for New York.
最早在市中心学校工作
From his first job teaching in inner-city schools,
其后的25年就职于议会
to his 25 year stint on the City Council...
这是谁的声音  我不知道
Whose voice is that? I don't know.
支持他的有"纽约时报"和"纽约邮报"
Endorsed by The New York Times, the New York Post,
以及我  迈克尔•福克斯
and me, Michael J. Fox.
迈克尔•福克斯  完了  我们完了
Michael J. Fox? It's over. We're finished.
如果迈克尔•福克斯支持他  那我也会投票给他的
If Michael J. Fox endorses him, then I'll vote for him.
听我说  迈克尔•福克斯没你想的那么厉害
Listen to me, Michael J. Fox is not as great a guy as you think.
拜托  他可是个圣人
Oh, no, no. Come on, he's a saint.
我听过这个磁带  算了吧  我不想听
I hear there's a tape. Forget it. I don't wanna hear it.
你已经进入稳定阶段了  迈克尔•福克斯
You've plateaued. Michael J. Fox.
注意  看着绿点
Pay attention. Follow the little green dot.
那就是你  我看图表不需要什么绿点
That's you there. I don't need a pointer to read a graph.
你看这个  安妮正在努力提升你  好吗
Well, read this. Annie's taken you as far as she can, okay?
这还没有结束
But it's not over.
你到底有多想要这个  没把握的事  我不做
How bad do you want this? I don't start things I can't win.
你想做到什么程度
Well, how far are you willing to go?
或者说  你想要我做到什么程度
Or should I say, how far do you want me to go?
我花那么多钱请你  不是让你来问我这些问题的
I pay you a lot of money for you not to ask me those types of questions.
好吗  盖伊
Okay, Guy-O?
明白了  老大
Rat-a-tat-tat, message received, boss.
早上好  给你做了早餐
Good morning. Made you breakfast.
你给我做早餐了
You made me breakfast.
嘿  我在想  你今天想跟我一起去工作吗
Hey, I was thinking maybe you would wanna go in to work with me today.
好啊  答应了
Cool. That'd be cool?
我去弄点喝的  好啊
I'll go make us drinks. All right.
快点  趁热吃
Don't let your food get cold.
好  这太好吃了
Okay. I won't. This is amazing.
安妮  你真厉害
Annie, you really outdid yourself.
安妮  你做的很成功
Annie, this is a triumph, honey.
我像只狗一样  在吃你做的早餐
You got me eating this thing up like a dog.
太好吃了  这是什么
This is good. What is it?
辣椒  牛汁
Paprika, oregano.
这又是什么  高达奶酪
What is... What is that, Gouda cheese?
你想知道高达奶酪是什么吗  吃了就知道了
You wanna know what's Gouda? This breakfast.
太赞了  直升机
Cool, a helicopter!
是的
Yeah.
要弯腰  为什么
Make sure you duck! Why?
我不知道  电影里都是这样
I don't know. They always duck in the movies!
快上去
Hop on up.
好了  坐好了
All right. Here we go.
你会晕机吗
Do you get airsick?
我不知道  我没坐过飞机
Don't know. I've never been in the air before.
我以前在秋千上吐过一次
I threw up on the swings once.
安妮  我们现在去检查手机信号塔  要确保没有问题
Annie, we're gonna do a cell tower check. Make sure they're all working.
这都是你自己做吗
You do that yourself?
是啊  我跟你说过这很有趣的
Yep, told you work was fun.
吉尔伯特  起飞吧
Gilbert, let's roll.
不会有事的
You'll be all right.
你知道"不漏接电话"  的秘密吗
You wanna know the secret to "Never drop a call"?
不知道
Not really.
我想  我想知道  特别想
Yes, yes, I do. Desperately.
很好
Good.
你看  我们的信号塔比其他手机要多5倍
See, we have five times as many cell towers as the other guys.
但是我们把它们藏在显眼的地方  就像那个  你看
But we hide them in plain sight. Like right there. You see?
没看到
No.
在她的王冠上
It's in her crown.
真是啊
Yeah!
太棒了
That's so cool.
很漂亮吧
It's beautiful, isn't it?
你是怎么做到的  你是怎么成为世界之王的
How'd you do this? How'd you become king of the world?
我才不是什么世界之王
Well, I wouldn't say king of the world.
但我工作很努力
But I work my butt off.
我越努力工作  机会就越多
The harder I work, the more opportunities I get.
你看  你得打好手里的牌
See, you gotta play the cards that you've been dealt,
不管手里的牌有多烂
no matter how bad the cards are.
要是手里没牌怎么办
What if you don't have any cards?
那你就虚张声势
Then you bluff.
这就是  我为什么喜欢这个城市
See, that's what I love about this city.
不管你是谁  干什么的
No matter who you are or what you are,
只要对你想要的  为之付出  你就会有所回报
you just gotta want it bad enough, and work with what you got.
This is just the start of your story
If you got guts, you'll get glory
Anyone can make their dreams come true
In New York City
And now's the time you gotta stand tough
'Cause if you work hard, you can rise up
Anyone can make it, even you
In New York City
Look at me, I'm just blood pumpin'
You and me are two hearts thumpin'
We are two souls feeling the same beat
So take it all, the city's yours
It's worth fighting for
It's all yours
So take it all
The city's yours
It's worth fighting for
It's all mine
It's all yours
要不去96号街上空看看吧
Why don't you go above 96th Street?
没问题
No reason.
吉尔伯特  去市郊
Gilbert, go uptown.
这就是我的纽约城
This is my New York City.
你住在哪里
Where'd you live?
四海为家
Everywhere.
我看到一个手机信号塔了  哪里
I see a cell tower! Where?
看到了吗  就在那
See it? Right there.
在恶鸟下面
Right under that devil bird.
好眼力
Good eyes.
你知道吗  安妮  有时候你要找的东西
You know, Annie, sometimes what you're looking for
就在你眼前
is right in front of your face.
In New York City
So take it all So take it all
The city's yours The city's mine
Worth fighting for It's worth fighting for
It's all mine It's all mine
So take it all So take it all
The city's yours The city's mine
Worth fighting for It's worth fighting for
It's all mine It's all mine
It's all yours
In New York City
格蕾丝
Grace.
96号街的实时交通状况怎样
What's our presence past 96th Street?
我们大多数都注意下面
Well, we're mostly focused below,
我试试看  可能要找一会儿
but I've been saying for a while we should try...
不用了  我找过的
No, but I had it this way.
我来  我找到了
Let me do this. I've got it.
我知道我在干什么
I know what I'm doing.
法雷尔小姐
Miss Farrell?
它到了  谢谢  是什么
It arrived. Thanks. What's that?
我买了一条裙子给安妮  今晚去参加活动
I bought a dress for Annie to wear to the event tonight.
很漂亮的
It's gorgeous.
你只要帮她绑蝴蝶结  确保绸子...
I just need you to tie the bow and make sure that the satin...
我绑蝴蝶结  对啊
I tie the bow? Yeah.
我帮她穿裙子  你只要帮她绑蝴蝶结
I'm dressing her? You just have to tie the bow.
什么样的蝴蝶结
No, I... What kind of bow?
就是个简单的蝴蝶结  就像活结一样吗
It's just a simple bow. Like a slipknot?
你要知道  我没参加过童子军  很简单的  威廉
'Cause you know I didn't take Boy Scouts. It's very easy, Will.
还有绸子  要弄出来  绸子
And have the satin facing out. The satin?
对  我知道有个女孩叫绸子
Yeah. I knew a girl named Satin.
我相信你  你不用跟我详细描述了
I'm sure you did. You don't need to elaborate.
绸子和蝴蝶结绝对不是我的强项  你知道吗  我会去的
Satin and bows is not necessarily my... You know what? I'll come over.
那好吧  太好了
Yeah, I mean, either way. Great.
她一定会很漂亮的
She's gonna look gorgeous.
安妮
Annie.
你没有
You did not...
你没看到什么吗  我什么也没看到
You didn't see anything? I didn't see anything.
很好  很好  因为我  我不知道  我以为我看到你
Good. Good. 'Cause I... Well, I don't know. I thought I saw you...
没有  我一直都在这里
Nope! Here the whole time.
你们刚刚在干什么  出去了吗
What were you guys doing? Just hanging out?
嗨  晚上好
Hi. Evening.
哇
Wow.
格蕾丝  你真漂亮
Grace, you look great.
得了  你也很帅气  英俊
Please. You look handsome, lovely.
没有  真的
No. Yes.
这很旧了  这是我奶奶的  没什么
This is old. This is my grandmother's. It's nothing.
你奶奶很漂亮
Your grandmother is hot.
我是说我没  我从没见过你奶奶  我没有
I mean, not that I've... I've never seen your grandmother. I'm not...
我是说这条裙子很漂亮
I'm saying that the dress is nice.
你真会说话
Well, you're sweet.
你很漂亮
You look good.
你也是
So do you.
我还没  快去换衣服
Let's go and get you dressed. Let's go!
她还没换  我已经换了
Her dressed. I was already dressed.
快点  对
Come on! Yes.
Come on. Yeah. Get some...
准备好了吗  我很期待
Ready? Yes. I'm very excited.
安妮  真漂亮  你太漂亮了
Annie, it's gorgeous. You're just gorgeous.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
好了  女士们  快走吧  我们就要迟到了
All right, ladies, let's go. Let's go. We're running late.
安妮  哇
Annie! Wow.
漂亮吧  我从没见过这么大的蝴蝶结
I know, right? I've never seen a bow this big.
是啊  我发现  你把绸子放在蝴蝶结外面
Yes, and I noticed that you put the satin on the outside of the bow.
这个想法真有趣
That's a very interesting choice.
你知道吗  你快出去  我们还没弄完
You know what? Get out of here. We're not done yet.
这里什么时候变成你们的了
You know what? When did this stop being my house?
出去  好吧
Out! Okay, fine.
你知道吗  一切都变了
You know what? You're changing everything.
实际上  这以前还是巴斯奎特
As a matter of fact, this used to be a Basquiat.
现在都是狗和鹿在草地上
Now it's a dog and a deer in a meadow.
这样的组合有什么可爱的
Why is that combination so cute?
过来  我们来梳头发
Come on. Let's do your hair.
你和斯塔克斯为什么不在一起呢
Why aren't you and Mr. Stacks together?
这是个复杂的问题
That's a complicated question.
一点也不复杂  你喜欢他吗
Not really. Do you like him?
我是他的下属  你知道的
Well, you know, I work for him. You know,
喜欢他也不能代表什么
liking him doesn't really come into play.
好吧
Okay.
他是我的朋友吗  是的  我觉得他有魅力吗  当然有
I mean, is he my friend? Yes. Do I find him attractive? Sure.
而且不只是感觉  他真的很帅
And not just in the physical sense. But he is very good-looking.
他的肩膀很好看  面部轮廓也很好
He's got lovely shoulders and a great, chiseled face.
嘴唇可爱  发型好看
Lovely lips. Good hair.
我不赞成他的发型  姐姐
I wouldn't bank on the hair, sister.
我还是太忙了  没空整这些事  所以．．．
Well, I'm far too busy to be bothered with anything like that anyway, so...
这话就像斯塔克斯说的一样
That sounds like something Mr. Stacks would say.
是吗
Yeah, it does, doesn't it?
我朋友佩珀  当她喜欢一个男生
When my friend Pepper liked this boy at school,
她就会用拳头打他
she punched him in the face.
后来她退学了  不过他们现在一起去公园玩
She got suspended, but they play in the park together now.
有时候我也想打斯塔克斯的脸
Sometimes I'd like to punch Mr. Stacks in the face.
我是说真正的打
I'm just meaning punching.
我真的想打他  他很讨人厌
That's it. I just want to punch him. He's annoying.
谢谢你做的这一切  威廉  你的名字在上面看起来很好
Thanks for doing this, Will. Your name's gonna look great up there.
你确定古根海姆  同意删除他们的名字
Now, you sure the Guggenheims are okay with me taking their name off?
你给了我无数个理由  可以不用管他们
You gave me 100 million reasons not to care.
他们找到我父母了吗
Did they find anything on my parents?
还没有  我们会尽力的  抱歉
No, not yet. And we dug real deep. I'm sorry.
谢谢
Thanks for trying.
安妮
Annie!
安妮  快过来  安妮
Annie, come on! Annie, Annie!
纽约人每天都会面临挑战
New Yorkers face challenges every single day.
看是不可逾越的挑战
Challenges that seem insurmountable.
我们都会对自己说"不"
We all tell ourselves "no" a lot.
我们说"我得不到那份工作的"
We say, "No, I won't get that job,"
或者"不  我付不起大学学费"
or, "No, I can't afford college."
除非你是富兰克林
Unless it's you, Franklin,
来自马沙文雅岛的穷街陋巷
coming from the mean streets of Martha's Vineyard.
嗨
Hey! Yeah.
我们把"不"  改成"好"
Let's change those noes to yeses.
因为你说不的时候  其实我们只是害怕说好
Because when we say no, we're actuallyjust scared to say yes.
所以我们要开始对自己说好
So, let's start saying yes to ourselves,
对美好的未来说好
and let's say yes to a brighter future.
你们大多数人都知道  最近有个小客人跟我一起住
Now, many of you know that I've had a visitor staying with me recently.
她只知道"好"  安妮
She only knows the word "yes." Annie?
你能上来一下吗
Could you come up, please?
去吧  你很棒的  快去吧  亲爱的
Go on. You'll be great. Go on, darling.
快咽下嘴里的虾  安妮
Swallow your shrimp, Annie.
安妮  我不想让你尴尬
Now, Annie, I don't wanna embarrass you.
我只想让各位看看  这个城市的未来是怎样的
I just want everyone to see what the future of our city is all about.
你有什么话想对这些
Now, do you have anything you want to say
心藏愧疚的好人说吗
to these good people that are just oozing with liberal guilt?
除了你  参议员
Except for you, Senator.
我知道你在反对
I know you're trying to build that fence.
我真不敢相信  我会来这里
I can't believe I'm here.
我穿着像云一样的裙子
I'm in a dress that feels like a cloud.
我站在一个巨型肉桂卷的中央
I'm standing in the middle of a giant cinnamon roll.
身边组合  他们拿着小提琴
With a band that has little violins,
大提琴
big violins,
还有那个
one of those.
钢琴
A piano.
斯塔克斯教会了我很多
Mr. Stacks has taught me so much.
他给了我一个很棒的机会
He's given me such a big opportunity.
Under the glow of the very bright lights
I turn my face towards the warm night skies
And I am not afraid of a thousand eyes
When they're above five hundred smiles
Oh, I used to think
Oh, she used to think
What wouldn't I give
What wouldn't she give
For a moment like this
This moment, this gift
Now look at me
And this opportunity
Is standing right in front of me
But one thing I know It's only part luck and so
I'm putting on my best show
Under the spotlight I'm starting my life
Big dreams becoming real tonight
So look at me and this opportunity
You're witnessing my moment, you see?
My big opportunity
Oh, I used to think
Oh, she used to think
What I wouldn't give
What wouldn't she give
For a moment like this
This moment, this gift
And now look at me
And this opportunity
Is standing right in front of me
But one thing I know It's only part luck and so
I'm putting on my best show
Under the spotlight I'm starting my life
Big dreams becoming real tonight
So look at me and this opportunity
You're witnessing my moment, you see?
我的伟大机会
My big opportunity
我不会浪费的
I won't waste it
我保证
I guarantee.
鞠躬
Take a bow.
太棒了
That was great.
现在读我写的演讲稿  什么
Now read my speech. What?
我给你写的演讲稿  就在那儿
That speech I wrote you. My speech. It's right there.
有什么问题吗
Is everything all right?
我帮她放大一点
I'll make it bigger for her.
这里开始"谢谢  斯塔克斯先生"
There it is. "Thank you, Mr. Stacks."
等一下  不要
Hold on a second. No.
安妮  有什么问题吗
Annie, is everything okay?
让我一个人  静一静
Leave me alone.
安妮  安妮
Annie! Annie!
安妮
Annie?
这是你们的大机会
This is your big opportunity
给威廉·斯塔克斯投票
To vote for William Stacks
安妮
Annie.
等等  等一下
Wait! Wait, wait, wait!
安妮
Annie!
嘿  等一下  安妮  慢点  你干什么
Hey! Wait, Annie. Slow down. What are you doin'?
安妮  等一下  我来
Annie. Wait, wait, wait. I got it.
怎么回事  没什么
What's going on? It's nothing.
小姑娘  你要告诉我  你现在是怎么回事
Young lady, you're have to tell me what's going on with you now!
不  我不要  你又不是我爸爸
No, I don't! You're not my dad.
哇
Wow.
我知道  我知道  我不是你爸爸
Well, I know that. I know I'm not your dad.
但是我想知道  你到底怎么了
But I would like to know what's going on with you.
我不会读
I can't read.
不会读是什么意思  我看你读过书啊  安妮
What do you mean you can't read? I've watched you read, Annie.
你可能只是太紧张了
Maybe you were just nervous.
抱歉  我搞砸了你的晚会
Sorry I ruined your shrimp event.
怎么回事  我不知道  她吓到了
What happened? I don't know. She freaked out.
嘿  你们俩之前在聊什么
Hey, what were you two talking about earlier?
她要我帮她找她父母  不过毫无希望
She asked me to help her find her parents, but it was a dead end.
即使找我警局的朋友  也帮不上忙
Even asked some of my old buddies on the force.
什么也找不到
There's nothing on that kid.
她的父母
Her parents.
太好了
Genius.
安妮  怎么了  往后退  让开
Annie, what's wrong? Get back! Hey, hey, get back!
格蕾丝  让开
Grace! Get back!
纳什  嘿
Nash! Hey!
让一让  她只是个孩子  让开  她只是个孩子
Make room! She's a kid. Get back. She's a kid.
拜托  让开  她只是个孩子
Come on. Get back. She's a kid!
谁啊
Who is it?
我是盖伊  我是威廉·斯塔克斯的下属
It's Guy Danlily. I work for Will Stacks.
进来
Come in.
你好
Hello there.
科琳·汉尼根
Colleen Hannigan?
那是我的婚前姓
That's my maiden name.
不过我还没有结婚  你明白我的意思吧
But I'm not married to it, if you know what I mean.
我可以再请你喝一杯吗
Can I buy you another drink?
要是他被选上了  我就会得到一笔钱
So, if he wins, I get paid a fortune.
比我之前得到的都要多
More than anything I've ever been paid combined.
为什么那么多
Why so much?
就像赌了一匹黑马一样
It's like getting paid long odds on a dark horse.
你知道  帮威廉·斯塔克斯赢得选举有多难吗
Do you know how hard it is to get Will Stacks elected?
"绝不漏接一个电话"  这有什么意义
"Never drop a call." What does that even mean?
现在大家都发短信了
Everybody texts now.
还有比他更糟的官员呢
There have been worse politicians than him.
我知道  是我帮他们选上的
I know. I got them elected.
施瓦辛格  金正日  那个卖钻石的家伙
Schwarzenegger, Kim Jong-Il, that blood diamonds guy.
什么  那都是过去的事了
What? But I'm over it.
我已经厌倦了  做一只人人需要的蟑螂  还要把我当作
I'm tired of being the cockroach everybody needs, but treats like a...
蟑螂  没错
Cockroach? Exactly.
干了这次我就不干了  拿了钱就退出
This is my last roll at the table. Get paid and get out.
根本就没有什么能够全身而退的  相信我
There's no such thing as a way out. Trust me.
一定会有办法全身而退的  相信我
There's always a way out. Trust me.
这次很特殊  只要找到安妮的父母
And in this particular case, it's all about finding Annie's parents.
我不想再做一只黑猫了
You know, I'm tired of being the black hat
整天围着疯人院团团转
Of running the show down in the snake pit
你在对我唱歌
Are you singing to me?
这是我们逃离这里的机会
So this is our chance to get out of this place
这不是幻觉吧
Is this really happening?
快起来  我们一起奔向
So come on, let's run for it to
康庄大道
Easy street
睡到自然醒
Where you sleep till noon
耶  耶  耶
Yeah, yeah, yeah
如果斯塔克斯帮安妮找到父母
If Stacks reunites Annie with her parents,
绝对有80%的人会投他
80% surge in the polls for sure.
我们已经聊过这个了  他们根本不存在
We talked about this already. They don't exist.
我们可以让他们存在
We'll make them exist.
找一对夫妇  假装成她的父母
Find a couple people to pretend to be her parents.
他们了解各种细节
They learn every detail
然后奇迹般的出现在选举之前  就可以了
and miraculously show up right before the election.
就这样  很快就有父母了
Add water, instant parents.
那我有什么好处
What's in it for me?
跟我得到的一样
Same as for me. Ka-ching.
不用再做蟑螂了
And no more being a cockroach.
我将成为一个不愁珠宝的大富婆
Yeah, I'll be the girl who's dripping in jewelry
我唱歌时  大家为我而疯狂
The crowds'll go wild when I sing
我不用再面临那个防火梯
I won't have to look out on a fire escape
是两个
Two.
马上就上排行榜
The view will be billboards of me
康庄大道  康庄大道
On easy street On easy street
Easy street Easy street
敬我们的出路
To a way out.
变成有钱人  变成有钱人
Where we all get paid Where we all get paid
耶  耶  耶  耶  耶
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah Yeah, yeah, yeah
行动起来  行动起来
Move them feet to Move them feet to
康庄大道  康庄大道
Easy street Easy street
等你到那儿了  等你到那儿了
When you get there When you get there
就别走了  就别走了
Stay Stay
我就知道我喜欢上你了
I knew I liked you.
好吧  那我们现在别这样  没事  没关系
Okay, we're not doing that right now. That's fine. Yolo, yolo. That's fine.
敬康庄大道
To easy street.
我告诉过她  她在这个城市  想干什么都可以
I've been telling her she can do anything she wants to do in this city,
但是我现在才发现  她竟然不会读书
and come to find out she can't even read.
怎么会这样
How does that happen?
不光是孩子迷失  威廉  很多大人也会迷失
A lot of kids get lost, Will. A lot of people get lost.
这不能接受
Well, it's unacceptable.
我们要给她找个家教
We gotta get her a tutor.
不过是为了她吧  这回不是为了媒体了
For her, though, right? Not just for the press.
是为了她
For her.
笑什么
What?
我能感觉到  你美丽动人的嘴唇  在微笑
I can feel you smiling with those Britisher-than-thou lips.
我会替你保守秘密的  蝙蝠侠
Your secret's safe with me, Batman.
什么秘密  你关心她
What secret? That you care about her.
我关心所有纽约的孩子
I care about the kids that are in New York City.
还有安妮
And Annie.
当然  她住在纽约
Well, she lives in New York.
所以她也受到关心
So, therefore, she's cared for.
是全部人  她也包括在内
It's a blanket... She's within the structure of the whatever.
安妮  你要去哪里
Annie? Where you going?
谢谢你做的一切  抱歉我昨晚搞砸了
Thanks for everything. Sorry I messed up last night.
希望你还能做市长
Hope you can still be mayor.
你在说什么  快回来
What are you talking about? Get back here.
没关系  这方面我很有经验
It's okay. I'm good at this part.
我经常被别人  赶出去
I've had a lot of practice getting kicked out of places.
安妮
Annie.
快把包放下  你哪儿也不许去
Listen, put your bag down. You're not going anywhere.
桑迪也要走  别说了
Sandy's gotta go. Stop it.
你和桑迪都待在这里  我不管昨天发生了什么
You and Sandy are staying here, and I don't care what happened last night.
不是  桑迪真的要走了
No, I mean Sandy's gotta go.
不  我是说...桑迪要走好
No, I mean... Sandy's gotta go. Okay.
是要香槟还是冰淇淋  什么
Well, is it champagne or gelato? What?
要山露汽水还是普通的饮料
Is it Mountain Dew or is it just plain old doo?
要柠檬水还是鸡块
Is it lemonade or chicken nuggets?
我也该走了  我也想去  因为我的膀胱都快爆了
I should go. Now I wanna go because my bladder's full.
快点  走吧
Come on, let's go.
我看到你签字了
I saw you sign your name.
你只想知道是怎么做到的吗
That's all you gotta know how to do.
但是你的老师呢  这是怎么做到的
But what about your teachers? How is this possible?
我善于隐藏
I'm good at hiding it.
在家呢  他们在家都没有发现吗
Okay, at home. They didn't catch it at home?
"在家"
"At home"?
你怎么没有告诉任何人
How come you didn't tell anybody about this?
首先  不是整个世界都会关心一个领养的孩子
It's not like the whole world wants a foster kid to begin with.
其次  这很丢人  我不想别人知道
And plus, it's embarrassing. I didn't want anyone to know.
你知道吗
You know what?
我想给你看样东西
I wanna show you something.
这里很不错
This is good here.
这是哪里  皇后区
Where are we? Queens.
我需要护照吗
Do I need my passport?
安妮  事实上  每个人都有
Truth is, Annie, everybody's got something
不想被别人知道的秘密
that they don't want anybody to know.
我也是
Including me.
对于我  这就是
For me, this is it.
这是我的家庭
This is my family.
你现在能看到他们吗
Can you see them right now?
看不到  但他们在我的脑海里
No, I don't. I see them in my mind.
就像这一段铁轨
Like this part of the track right here?
这是我父亲建造的  每天工作20个小时
This is where my father worked 20 hours a day.
除了工作  还是工作
Work, and work, and work, and work.
然后他死了
And then he died.
那时我12岁
I was 12 years old.
他长什么样子
What was he like?
我不知道  我几乎不了解他  他总是在工作
I don't know. I barely knew him. He was always working.
这就是我为什么觉得  如果我工作的够努力的话
And that's why I felt like if I worked hard enough,
那我就有可能  离他更近了
then that'd probably bring me closer to him.
所以我有了这个
And that's why I developed this.
好吧
Well,
现在  你有了这个
now, you got this.
是啊  安妮
Yeah, all right, Annie.
我眼睛里好像有花粉什么的  好痛
You know, this pollen or something's got my eyes all scratchy.
我们走这边吧  我们还可以看到火车要去哪里
Let's walk this way. We can see where the trains go.
这么多年没见了  见到你真好
It's so good to see you after all these years!
西装男  少废话  你要先登记
Yo, suit. No cuts, no butts, no coconuts. You gotta sign in.
为什么  试演
For what? The auditions.
试演
Audition?
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
等下
Wait!
"我们一直都在找你"
"We've been trying so hard to find you!"
她在哪里  在后面  怎么了
Where is she? Back there. Why?
等下
Wait!
嘿  站住  站住
Hey! Stop! Stop!
等下
Wait!
这个想法很有趣
That's an interesting choice.
"噢  亲爱的孩子  这么多年没见  见到你真好
"Oh, darling girl! It's so good to see you after all these years!"
"我们一直在找你"
"We've been trying so hard to find you,
"后来我们看到  你和竞选市长的男神在一起的照片"
"and then we saw pictures of you with the nice man running for mayor."
"我们来唱一首特别的  只有我们3个人知道的歌"
"Let's sing our special song only us three know."
盒式吊坠
Locket!
The sun will come out
Pronto!
Bet your sweet bottom, fella, that Bet your sweet bottom, fella, that
There'II be sun!
这是怎么回事
What the hell is this?
太糟糕了
A disaster.
你是垃圾  你是一坨屎
You're garbage. You're pitchy.
下一组  拜托
Next! Come on.
我很喜欢这个台词  大卫·克雷默来过了
I really like the script. David Kramer says hello!
快出去  白痴
Out! That hack.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
是你说要找两个人来演她的父母
You told me to find two people to play her parents.
我是说找朋友或邻居
I meant some friends or some neighborhood toughs.
不是公开试演
Not open auditions.
这些人都很糟糕  我知道
These are callbacks. I know, right?
他们为什么还要唱歌  大家喜欢音乐
And why are they singing? People love musicals.
用音乐开头不需要理由  这样十分有魔力
Bursting into song for no apparent reason. It's magical!
这儿有窗  这儿有床
There's a window There's a bed
这儿有桌子  这儿有你的头
Here's a table There's your head
好了  够了
Okay. You're done.
我去找父母  你什么也不用做
I'll take care of finding the parents. You don't do anything.
等我需要你了  再打给你
I'll call you when I need you.
但是  没有但是  我们没有时间了
But... No buts. We're running out of time.
摸一下指示牌  我摸到了
Touch the sign! I did it!
你有没有见过鬼马小精灵呕吐
You ever see Casper the Friendly Ghost throw up?
没有
No.
你喜欢棉花糖吗
Would you like a marshmallow?
全麦饼干怎么样  你这个混
Psych! How about a graham cracker? You son of a...
你笑死我了
You make me laugh.
嘿  格蕾丝  我问你一件事
Hey, Grace. Let me ask you something.
想成为一个监护人  到底有多难
Exactly how hard would it be to become a foster parent?
而且不是暂时的  就像
And not temporarily either. More like a...
你知道的  那种永久性的
Well, you know, permanent situation.
你是说  要领养安妮
You mean, adopt Annie?
是的  不管用什么词
Yeah, well, whatever the word is.
就是这个词  威廉
That's the word, Will.
那
Then...
好
Yeah.
桑迪
Sandy.
我们在床上睡觉了
We slept in the bed.
你更喜欢哪一个  威廉
Which one do you prefer, Will?
红色
Red.
已经两个小时了  我觉得她完全学会识字了
It's been two hours. I don't think she's completely learned to read yet.
嗯  不是完全  不过
Yeah, well, not completely, but...
威廉  威廉
Will! Will!
我们找到变革者了
We got our game changer.
每个竞选都有一个变革者  我们找到我们的变革者了
Every election needs a game changer. We got our game changer.
别再说"变革者"了  安妮的父母
Stop saying "game changer." Annie's parents.
他们看到她的照片  他们打电话给我们了  这就是奇迹
They saw her picture, and they called us. It's a miracle.
"变革者"  很明显  他们这些年一直在找她
"Game changer." Apparently, they've been looking for her for years,
但她不在失踪儿童的系统里
but she's not in the system.
他们怎么知道  她就是他们的女儿
How do they know she's their daughter?
他们了解她的一切  他们知道盒式吊坠  纸条
Well, they know everything about her. They know about the locket, the note,
我还帮他们做了DNA测试
and oh, yeah, I ran a DNA test.
这下好了
Boom goes the dynamite.
DNA  测试
DNA test.
好的  先别告诉安妮
All right, but don't tell her.
我想在安妮知道之前  先见见他们
I wanna meet them before Annie finds out.
好的  没问题  不过应该由你
I wouldn't have it any other way. I mean, you should totally be the one
来告诉安妮  是我们找到她的父母
who tells Annie that we found her parents!
你找到我父母了
You found my parents?
是的  亲爱的  我们找到了  真的吗
Yes, honey, we did. Well, we think so. Really?
是的  我们要去一个叫多玛尼的餐馆  见他们
Yeah. We're gonna meet them at a place called the Domani.
那就是留下纸条的地方  不会吧
That's where the note is from! No way!
我就知道他们会来找我的
I knew they'd come for me.
安妮  我真替你高兴  我知道这是你一直想要的
I'm happy for you, Annie. I know this is what you always wanted.
这都要谢谢你
And it's all because of you.
我真不敢相信  我就要看到我父母了  我有点害怕
I can't believe I'm gonna see my parents. I'm kind of freaking out.
安妮  安妮  快过来
Annie! Annie! Over here!
你开心吗  你开心吗
Are you happy? Are you happy?
我们真替你高兴  谢谢
Very happy for you. Thanks.
安妮与父母重聚
Annie, The Reunion.
安妮  我的女儿
Annie. My girl.
能匹配吗  我看看
Is it a match? Let's see, huh?
刚好吻合
It's a match.
我们还以为要永远失去你了呢  我也是
We thought we'd lost you forever. Me, too.
我们一直过得不好
We fell upon hard times.
我们觉得  让别人来照顾你  那样会更好
We just felt it was best for someone else to look after you.
我明白
I figured.
我一直都无法原谅我自己
I've never forgiven myself for it.
但是我们回去找你的时候  我们又找不到你了  孩子
But when we got back on our feet, well, we just couldn't find you, kid.
不过天使一直在照顾你
But the angels were looking out.
你们住在哪里  新泽西
Where do you live? New Jersey.
不过我们搬到巴西了  因为我的工作调动
But we're moving to Brazil for my job.
我觉得你会喜欢那里的  太好了
I think you're gonna like it there. Cool.
好了  我们开始吧
Okay, let's get started.
一切都很顺利
Everything is in order.
我们还有法官签字的  DNA测试结果
We have the DNA test signed by the judge.
现在  我们只需要家长签字了
Now, we just need signatures of the parents.
叫你们呢  叫我们
That's you guys. That's us.
女士  签在这里
Ma'am, sign right there.
嘿  还记得我吗
Hey. Remember me from before?
我记得  是的
You know what, I do. That's right.
我不知道你是安妮的养母
I didn't know that you were Annie's foster mom.
除此之外  还有其他  我知道
Amongst other things. I know.
她说你是个好歌手
She said that you're a very good singer.
她怎么说的"她是个好歌手"
What'd she say? "She's a really good singer."
没有  她没有这样
No, she didn't do any of that.
她只说了你的声音很好听  她很喜欢
She just said you have a very nice voice, and she liked it.
她真这么说  是的
She did? Yep.
她说听了后感觉很好
Said it made her feel good about herself.
谢谢  罗德尼
Thank you, Rodney.
前监护人
The guardian of record.
来签字  快过来
That's you, stretch. Come on. Right here.
你真觉得没问题吗
You sure about this?
你是说赢得竞选吗  没问题
That this is gonna win you the election? Yeah.
不是  是安妮
No. Annie.
你给我工资  没让我担心她
You don't pay me to worry about her.
还有现任临时监护人  威廉·斯塔克斯
And the current temporary guardian, William Stacks.
斯塔克斯  我们又见面了
Mr. Stacks, we meet again.
这支笔真大
That is a very big pen.
谢谢
Thank you.
好了  根据纽约的法律
Okay. Well, according to the State of New York,
你们正式成为一家人了
you are officially reunited.
耶  太好了
Yay! Great!
我们4点再多来接你  好的
We'll pick you up at 4:00. Great.
好了
All right.
他们怎么样
What were they like?
嘿  等一下
Hey! Wait!
你是怎么做DNA测试的
How did you do the DNA test?
有钱能使鬼推磨
You can do anything with money.
那两个人是谁  你打算怎么处理她
Well, who are those people, and what's your plan with her, anyhow?
这你就别管了  她达到她的目的了
Don't worry about it. She served her purpose.
什么意思
What does that mean?
他们会收养安妮一段时间
That they'll hold her for a while
然后选举完了后  再把她扔回收养所
then dump her back in the system till after the election.
没伤害  没损失
No harm, no foul.
你不能那么对她  她还只是个小孩子
You can't do that to her. I mean, she's still a little girl.
你关心这些做什么  还是闭嘴回家歇着吧
What do you care? Look, just go home and keep your mouth shut.
嘿  你不能这样跟我讲话
Hey! You can't talk to me like that.
我都知道你做的这些事
I know things about you.
如果你知道什么对你有好处
Well, if you know what's good for you,
你就回家吧  把你的嘴管好
you'll go home, and keep your mouth shut.
斯塔克斯先生  这会对你的投票有帮助吗
Mr. Stacks! Has it helped you in the polls?
嘿  伙计们  斯塔克斯替安妮能够重聚而感到很高兴
Hey, folks, Mr. Stacks is thrilled for Annie and her family.
绝不落下一个市民  投斯塔克斯做市长
Never drop a citizen. Vote Stacks for mayor.
安妮  安妮  你看到他们开心吗  感觉如何
Annie! Annie! Did you enjoy seeing them? How was it?
我们会想你的  安妮  是啊
We're gonna miss you, Annie. Yeah.
我们终于可以把那些泡泡  搬出去了
We can finally get those bubbles out of the apartment.
嗯
Yeah.
不冷吧
Warm enough?
不冷  你呢
Yeah. Are you?
不冷
Yeah.
眼睛里是不是又进灰了
Is it dusty in here?
没有
Nah.
"纽约邮报"报道
The New York Post reports
威廉·斯塔克斯帮助安妮  找到亲生父母
Will Stacks reuniting Annie with her parents
将会协助他竞选市长
has pushed him into a dead heat in the race for mayor.
他的投票又多了30个点
He was once trailing by as much as 30 points.
嘿  宝贝  你从没来过这里
Hey, baby. So, I haven't seen you in here for a minute.
有什么我能为你效劳的吗  放松点
To what do I owe this pleasure? Take it easy.
你好吗
How you doing?
不太好
Not super awesome.
我给你做个三文治吧
You want me to make you a sandwich?
要不我给你配把钥匙
How about if I make you a key?
你有没有遇到过  前一秒你还觉得是个好主意
You ever do anything that you thought was really a good idea at the time,
但是下一秒  你又没那么确定了
but then after, it's like you're not so sure.
有啊  贴上这个配钥匙的指示牌
Yeah. Putting up that key sign.
其实我一点都不了解  怎么配钥匙
I don't know the first thing about making keys.
发生什么事了  宝贝  你做什么了
What's the matter, sweetie? What did you do?
不管什么事  我都会帮你的
'Cause, whatever it is, you know I'm here to help.
我这么对你  你为什么还要对我这么好
Why are you so nice to me, the way I treat you?
因为经历过这些辛酸后  就会有位漂亮大方的女人在等我
Because under all that bitter, there's a sweet lady with a big heart.
她只是出去一会儿  没事的
She's just been gone for a while. That's all.
嗯
Yeah.
我是谁  我又变成了谁
Who am I, and what have I become?
我到底是图啥  是钱吗
Do I stand for something or for money?
我是谁  我心中那善良的女孩儿去哪儿了
Who am I, and where's my good girl gone?
我曾经是多么的善良
You know I had a good heart once, you see
我是谁  现在我的盔甲没了
Who am I now that my armor's gone?
你给了我很多  我却才刚刚发觉
You gave me what I didn't know I needed
我是谁  现在是我的心赢了吗
Who am I now that my heart is won?
我之前还不知道  我也会需要一个人
I didn't know I needed anyone
不过  我走到了今天
But I've got today But I've got today
我要付出
I gotta make I gotta make
我最大的努力
The best I can of it The best I can of it
因为昨天已经  逝去  因为昨天已经逝去
'Cause yesterday is dead and gone 'Cause yesterday is dead and gone
只有我随同一起  随同一起
And me along with it And me along with it
我想重新开始
I want to start again I want to start again
所以我会四处寻找
So I look within So I look within
记住自己想要什么
Remember what I wanted Remember what I wanted
因为我不知道
'Cause I don't know 'Cause I don't know
我变成什么样的人
Who I've become Who I've become
但我始终相信
But I will trust in it But I will trust in it
我会始终相信的
Yeah, I will trust in it Yeah, I will trust in it
我是谁  我花费了一生
Who am I? I spent my life alone
寻找一个叫做家的地方
Forever looking for some place to call home
我是谁  将要遇到我自己
Who am I? About to meet myself
这应该是好事  但是好像哪里不对
This should feel right, but something don't
找想重新开始
I want to start again
所以我四处寻找
So I look within
记住我想要的
Remember what I wanted
因为我不知道  我变成了怎样的人
'Cause I don't know who I've become
不过我始终相信
But I will trust in it
我会始终相信的
I will trust in it
但是今晚  我要付出
But today I gotta make
我最大的努力
The best I can of it
因为昨天已经逝去
'Cause yesterday is dead and gone
我会随之一起
And me along with it
我想重新开始
I wanna start again.
小鬼们  我要你们帮忙
Guys, I need your help.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
把这个还给你  这个去巴西也没用
Gotta give this back to you. It won't work in Brazil.
是啊  我们还没去过巴西
Yeah, we're not in Brazil yet.
我们去了厄瓜多尔  玻利维亚  哥伦比亚
We're in Ecuador, Bolivia, Colombia...
其实是南哥伦比亚  波哥大  那个地方太糟糕了
Actually, southern Colombia. Now, Bogota, that's a tough place to penetrate.
我听说过波哥大
Yeah, I've heard that about Bogota.
给你画了一幅画  真的吗
Made you something. Really?
这是我  这是桑迪  这是你
That's me, that's Sandy, and that's you.
"斯塔克斯"  是我从手机上抄下来的
I copied "Stacks" from my phone.
我会想你的
I'm gonna miss you.
安妮  嗨
Annie. Hi.
你准备好了吗  我们直接去机场  孩子
You ready? We're gonna go straight to the airport, kid.
好啊
Okay.
认识你真好  安妮
It's been great getting to know you, Annie.
你是个很特别的女孩
You're such a special little girl.
你应该冲斯塔克斯脸上打一拳
You should punch Mr. Stacks in the face
这样你就可以跟他一起去公园玩了
so you can go play in the park together.
这样你就有真正的朋友了
Then you'll have a real friend.
这是我们之间的秘密  好吗  好
That was between us! Okay? Okay.
我想给你们减轻一点负担
I'd like to help you out.
不用  谢谢你  我们不能收
No, thank you. We don't believe in handouts.
我们只要安妮  你已经给我们了
Only hand ups. And you've already given us one.
再见  安妮
Bye, Annie.
要幸福下去  你也是
Never slow your roll. You neither.
狗狗真可爱
What a cute dog.
走吧  再见
Come on. Bye.
再见
Bye.
再见  安妮
Goodbye, Annie.
媒体就爱吃这套  我们以压倒性的优势赢了
The press is eating this up. We're gonna crush.
再见  哈罗德·格雷  你这个可怜的公益空想家
Goodbye, Harold Gray, you pathetic, nonprofit do-gooder.
格蕾丝  手机电池的事情怎么样了
Grace, where are we with that phone battery?
什么
What?
一周的续航  那件事进展怎么样了
A full week on one charge, where are we with that?
我们就快完成了  那就是还没有完成
We're close. Close is not good enough.
我们没有  我们已经浪费很多时间了
Well, we don't have the... We've already wasted enough time.
我要召集研发部门
I'm gonna go call the research department.
要听话  孩子
Knock them dead, kid.
再见  安妮
Bye, Annie!
威廉  我不喜欢看到你这样
Will? I hate seeing you like this.
格蕾丝  我没事  我们
Grace, I'm fine. Let's just...
斯塔克斯先生  我觉得你得听听这个
Mr. Stacks, I think you're gonna wanna hear this.
安妮有麻烦了
Annie's in trouble.
什么  那不是她亲生父母
What? Those weren't her real parents.
什么  怎么回事  别理她  她肯定是疯了
What? What is happening? Ignore her, 'cause she's clearly insane.
说话注意点  混蛋
Watch your mouth, chango.
我做了一件坏事  我真的很遗憾
Look, I did something terrible, and I'm really sorry.
你说他们不是她亲生父母是什么意思
What do you mean those aren't her real parents?
他让他们把她带到别的地方
He had them take her somewhere.
我真不敢相信  我竟然跟你跳舞  你跟他跳舞了
I can't believe I danced with you! You danced with him?
当时我很绝望  他又有点动手动脚的
I was desperate. He was a little handsy.
安妮在哪儿  你干什么了
Where is Annie? What have you done?
安妮在哪儿
Where's Annie?
巴西冷不冷
Is it cold in Brazil?
有点冷  她在问你问题
Just be cool. She's asking questions.
你在收集烟灰缸吗  没有
Do you collect ashtrays? No.
艺术品  没有
Art? No.
你会弹钢琴吗  闭嘴
Do you play piano? Just shut up.
我们要去哪里
Where are we going?
我们要带你去个地方  就一段时间
We're just taking you someplace for a little bit. Just relax.
你们不是我的亲生父母  是不是
You're not my real parents, are you?
坐好  别动  你干什么  别这样
Sit back. Sit still. What are you doing? Stop that.
放我走  等斯塔克斯发现了
Let me go! When Mr. Stacks finds out about this...
斯塔克斯再也不需要你了  要不然我们为什么要带走你
Stacks doesn't need you anymore. Why do you think we're taking you?
你是斯塔克斯的手下  他才不会这么做的
You work for Mr. Stacks? He wouldn't do this.
我觉得他已经拍了足够多的照片了
Yeah, well, I guess he has enough photos.
这是斯塔克斯干的
Mr. Stacks did this?
召集FBI所有人手  我要所有人都出动
Call my guy at the FBI. I want to get everyone on it.
我知道
I got it.
我已经让警察负责了
I'm already on with the police.
我以为不会发生这种事
I didn't think anything like this could happen.
你怎么会不知道她是怎样的人
How could you not know who has her?
我有手下负责这种事
I got a guy who takes care of these kinds of things.
我们没必要插手  相信我
It keeps our hands clean. Trust me.
我怎么可能相信你  你把安妮带走了
I can't trust you. You took Annie.
嘿
Hey!
嘿  听着
Hey, look!
是我  安妮
It's me! Annie!
嘿  有个女孩  救命
Hey, girl! Help!
快抓住她  快抓住她
Get her. Grab her.
坐好  快坐好  别碰我
Sit, sit, sit still. Don't touch me!
别动
Sit still!
所有人  都听好
Everybody, listen up.
查一下方圆10公里内的每一个电话  好的
Check every call within a 10-mile radius. On it.
我就知道他们可以查到
I knew they could do that!
有人把安妮的照片  发到微博上了
Someone just posted a picture ofAnnie on Twitter.
在哪儿  54号和6号街
Where? 54th and 6th.
还有一条关于安妮的博客  她好像在挥手
Another one on an Annie blog. It looks like she's waving.
好像是57号到6号街  我们走
57th and 6th. Let's go.
嘿  你要是去的话  所有人都会知道的
Hey. You do this, and everyone will know.
别再想着当什么市长了  你会把一切都毁掉的
Forget about being mayor. It'll destroy your whole business!
我不在乎
I don't care.
你这是犯一个天大的错误  想想你之前付出的一切
You're making a huge mistake. Think about everything you've worked for.
这都不重要了
That everything means nothing.
你走人吧
You're fired.
你去跟他说说
You! Talk to him.
他只听你的
You're the only one he'll listen to.
你这样  她不会喜欢你的
It's not 'cause she likes you.
她打人还真疼
She's got these pointy little...
这飞机不错  这是什么  贝尔4297
Nice chopper! What is this, a Bell 4297
你说什么
What?
怎么了  我这种家伙不能了解直升机吗
What, a guy like me can't know about helicopters?
其实我对直升机一点也不懂  都写在这里
I don't know anything about helicopters! It's written right here.
吉尔伯特  我们走吧  收到了
Gilbert, let's go. Roger that.
"收"  是谁
Who's Roger? Who's Roger?
有人晕机吗
Is anyone else dizzy?
看  是安妮  救命
Look! It's Annie! Help.
又发了一张照片  65号和10号街
Another picture on lnstagram. 65th and 10th.
往西边去  吉尔伯特
Head west, Gil.
嘿  你在干什么  嘿
Hey, what are you doing? Hey!
让她别动
Hold her still.
我们会找到她的  威廉
We'll find her, Will.
又有一条是在华盛顿大桥发的
Just posted on the George Washington Bridge.
她在挥手  她是故意挥手的
She's waving. She's doing it on purpose!
去郊区  吉尔
Head uptown, Gil.
在那里
There she is!
别跟丢了
Don't lose them.
又有一条博客  他正前往国家公园的方向
On an Annie blog! She's heading to the State Park.
他们去往公园
They're headed into the park.
吉尔伯特  你要小心点
Gilbert, don't make me come up there and fly this helicopter.
他们在那儿
There they are!
安妮  安妮
Annie! Annie! Annie!
她听不见的
I don't think she can hear you.
不是吧  警察
What? It's the cops.
不是的  是斯塔克斯
Oh, no. It's Stacks.
他为什么要跟着我们
Why would he be following us?
小心  哇
Watch it! Whoa!
小心
Watch out!
安妮  安妮
Annie! Annie.
吉尔伯特  在这里着陆  截住他们
Gil, let's land this! Cut them off.
我真的希望能快点找到安妮
I really hope we find Annie soon.
不要
No!
安妮
Annie!
抓住他们
Get them!
纽约警察  别动
NYPD, hold it!
安妮
Annie!
安妮  你没事吧  我没事  我们扯平了
Annie, are you okay? I'm fine. We even now?
什么  还想拍照吗
What? Want another photo?
不是这样的  亲爱的  就是这样
It's not like that, honey. It's exactly like that.
你根本不关心我  我只不过是你的棋子
You don't care about me. I was just an opportunity to you.
不是的  这不是真的  就是真的
No, that's not true. It is true.
你对我做的这一切  都是你为了当一个愚蠢的市长
You did all this to me so you could be stupid mayor!
不是的  听我说  你要相信我
No... Listen, you gotta trust me!
我不会相信你的  我不会相信任何人
I can't trust you. I can't trust anybody!
不要  让我走
No! Just let me go!
听着  发生这种事  我很抱歉
Listen, I'm sorry for what happened to you.
我不能看着你的眼睛
I can't look you in the eye
跟你说我不知道发生了什么事
and tell you that I didn't know that something was going on.
但是我真的不知道  他们不是你的亲生父母
But I did not know that those people weren't your parents.
你要相信我
You gotta believe me.
这就是你  安妮
This is you, Annie.
这就是你
It's you.
等等  等等
Wait, wait.
先生
Sir! Sir.
我正式宣布退出竞选市长
I officially withdraw from this mayoral race.
我相信有人比我更适合这个职位
I think that this city deserves someone better than I am.
我要花更多的时间
I wanna take time out to concentrate on things
去关注我最重要的人
that really matter to me the most,
那就是这个了不起的小女孩  安妮
and that's this amazing little girl, Annie.
因为
Because...
眼睛进灰了
It's kind of dusty.
不是灰
No, it's not dusty.
是我哭了
I'm crying.
她是我的家人
That's my family.
谢谢
Thank you.
我还要你答应我一件事
I need one more thing from you.
你总是这么古灵精怪  什么事
You are always on the hustle. What is it now?
别再玩游戏了
Stop playing games.
噢  对  我明白了
Oh, yeah, I got this.
你还好吗  我没事
You all right? I'm fine.
格蕾丝  我自己总是不能很好的意识到
Grace, listen, I've always had a problem with realizing
什么才是对的
what's right in front of me,
我正在学习
and, well, I'm learning.
你愿意跟我共进晚餐吗
Would you like to go out to dinner with me?
什么
What?
要是没有你  我一事无成
I mean, without you, I can't function.
这不只是工作方面
That just doesn't mean work either.
所有事  你都是对的
You're right about everything.
手机你说对了  盖伊你也说对了
You're right about the phone, you're right about Guy,
市长竞选  你也说对了  风向你也
you're right about this mayoral race, right about the wind...
别说了
Shut up!
终于在一起了
Together at last!
永远在一起
Together forever!
我们打个结
We're tying a knot
他们永远也解不开
They never can sever!
我不需要太阳把天空变蓝
I don't need sunshine now To turn my skies to blue
除了你  我什么都不要
I don't need anything but you!
你用你可爱的小手
You've wrapped me around
缠绕着我
That cute little finger
你把我的生活  写成了歌
You've made life a song
你让我变成一名歌手
You made me a singer!
你不温不热
You're not warm and fuzzy
你不是最好的女孩儿
And ain't the most shyest girl
但是地球上没有什么
But nothing on Earth But nothing on Earth
能够分离我们
Could ever divide us! Could ever divide us!
今天太可怕了
Today was terrible.
今天简直就是个噩梦
Today was a straight-up nightmare.
但是那已成过去
But that was then But that was then
因为我一直在寻找一样东西
'Cause I was looking for something 'Cause I was looking for something
寻找我生命的最后篇章
Looking for my loose end Looking for my loose end
但是现在除了你  我什么都不需要
Now I don't need anything but you Now I don't need anything but you
不过后来
But that was then But that was then
我一直在寻找
I was looking for something I was looking for something
寻找我生命的最后篇章
Looking for my loose end Looking for my loose end
但是现在除了你  我什么都不需要
Now I don't need anything but you Now I don't need anything but you
地球上没有什么
But nothing on Earth But nothing on Earth
可以分离我们
Could ever divide us! Could ever divide us!
地球上没有什么
But nothing on Earth But nothing on Earth
可以分离我们
Could ever divide us! Could ever divide us!
地球上没有什么
But nothing on Earth But nothing on Earth
可以分离我们
Could ever divide us! Could ever divide us!
地球上没有什么
But nothing on Earth But nothing on Earth
可以分离我们
Could ever divide us! Could ever divide us!
对  很好
Yeah, all right.
让我们跳起来
Everybody dance now
不行  这是他们的事  妈咪
No, no. It's their thing, mami.
终于在一起了
Together at last!
永远在一起
Together forever!
我们打个结
We're tying a knot
他们永远都解不开
They never can sever! They never can sever!
你俩是
You're two of a kind
最幸福的一对
The happiest pair now
就像流星一样闪亮
Like bright shooting stars
欣喜若狂
You're floating on air now
这就是梦想成真吗
And what's the title of the dream that just came true?
我什么也不要
I don't need anything
不要  不要
Anything Anything
除了你们  我什么也不要
I don't need anything but you
像他那样不停唱歌跳舞  他不可能赢的
Keeps singing and dancing like that, there's no way he was ever gonna win.
这座城市充满了机遇  就靠你们去把握
"The city is full of opportunity. It's yours to take.
明天太阳照样升起
"The sun will come out tomorrow."
The sun'II come out tomorrow
Bet your bottom dollar that tomorrow
There'II be sun
Just thinkin' about tomorrow
Clears away the cobwebs and the sorrow
'Til there's none
When I'm stuck with a day
That's gray, and lonely
I just stick out my chin and grin
And say
The sun'II come out tomorrow
So you gotta hang on 'til tomorrow
Come what may
Tomorrow, tomorrow! But nothing on Earth
I love you, tomorrow! Could ever divide us
You're always a day away! But nothing on Earth
Could ever divide us Tomorrow!
But nothing on Earth Tomorrow!
Could ever divide us I love you, tomorrow
You're always a day
Away!
To-To-To-To-Tomorrow... Tomorrow is a day away!
Yeah!
好样的  莎佛朗
You do you, Saffron!
这就是我想说的
That's what I'm talking about.